<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Native Bee Bot</title> <link>http://twitter.com/nativebeebot</link><description>@nativebeebot</description>
<item><title>The use of digital video recorders in pollination biology</title><description>1. Digital video recording (DVR) devices, such as the GoPro Hero, have the potential to greatly benefit pollination ecology, but the advantages of digitally recording pollinator activity over direct human observation have not been formally assessed.2. Two plant taxa, Lavandula angustifolia and Canna ‘sp.’, with differing floral morphology, were used to compare the value of DVR and direct observations in estimating honeybee (Apis mellifera) visitation, flower density and number of flowers visited per foraging bout.3. The two methods yielded identical results when observing the structurally simple L. angustifolia at both high (10.54 ± 0.52 per plant) and low honeybee density (2.24 ± 0.20 per plant). However, DVR underestimated the number of flowers scored in the field of view (28.7 ± 1.8 direct vs. 22.7 ± 0.9 DVR), the number of honeybees observed (5.3 ± 0.8 direct vs. 3.7 ± 0.7 DVR) and the number of flowers visited during foraging bouts (8.3 ± 1.2 direct vs. 5.5 ± 1.0 DVR) on the more complex Canna ‘sp.’4. It is concluded that portable weatherproof DVR devices such as the GoPro Hero are valuable tools for pollination biologists, allowing a single researcher to make simultaneous observations of multiple plants in one or more sites, whilst also allowing the footage to be reviewed. However, DVR devices are limited by their depth and field of view when target plants are large or structurally complex.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12394</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12394</guid></item>
<item><title>Save the bees? There's an app for that</title><description>(University of Vermont) A new mobile app can calculate the crop productivity and pollination benefits of supporting endangered bees.</description><link>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-02/uov-stb021717.php</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-02/uov-stb021717.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Bee decline threatens US crop production</title><description>(University of Vermont) The first-ever study to map US wild bees suggests they are disappearing in the country's most important farmlands.</description><link>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-02/uov-bdt021717.php</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 21:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2017-02/uov-bdt021717.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Researchers use big-brother tech to spy on bumblebees</title><description>By tagging individual bumblebees with microchips, biologists have gained insights into the daily life of a colony of bumblebees (Bombus impatiens) in unprecedented detail. The team found that while most bees are generalists collecting both pollen and nectar over the course of their lifetime, individual workers tend to specialize on one of the two during any given day, dedicating more than 90 percent of their foraging sorties to either pollen or nectar. The observations also revealed that individual bumblebee workers differ vastly in terms of their foraging activity.</description><link>https://phys.org/news/2017-02-big-brother-tech-spy-bumblebees.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 02:18:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>news406617473</guid></item>
<item><title>Honey bee genetics sheds light on bee origins</title><description>Where do honey bees come from? A new study clears some of the fog around honey bee origins. The work could be useful in breeding bees resistant to disease or pesticides.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/02/170217012456.htm</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 22:24:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/02/170217012456.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Honey bee genetics sheds light on bee origins</title><description>Where do honey bees come from? A new study from researchers at the University of California, Davis and UC Berkeley clears some of the fog around honey bee origins. The work could be useful in breeding bees resistant to disease or pesticides.</description><link>https://phys.org/news/2017-02-honey-bee-genetics.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 12:47:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>news406482385</guid></item>
<item><title>Surprised honeybees give 'whooping signal' in the hive, study shows</title><description>A honeybee signal – widely thought to be used by bees in the hive to prevent one another from advertising the location of food – could also be a response to being startled or surprised, according to scientists.</description><link>https://phys.org/news/2017-02-honeybees-whooping-hive.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 05:20:55 -0800</pubDate><guid>news406369248</guid></item>
<item><title>Discovery of wood nesting by a subterranean halictine bee, Lasioglossum (Evylaeus) vulsum (Hymenoptera: Halictidae)</title><description>AbstractAn unusual nesting substrate of a subterranean halictine bee, Lasioglossum (Evylaeus) vulsum (Vachal), was found at Mt Ishizuchi-san, Ehime, Japan. Two nests were obtained from a decaying log in a display sign for a local restaurant. Brood cells, forming a cell cluster, were constructed in a wood hollow with rotted wood fibers pressed together. Nests in the decaying log show the same structural elements as those made in soil. This is the first report of wood nesting by subterranean halictine bees belonging to the subgenus Evylaeus.An unusual nesting substrate of the subterranean halictine bee Lasioglossum (Evylaeus) vulsum (Vachal) was found at Mt Ishizuchi-san, Ehime, Japan. Two nests were obtained from a decaying log of a display sign for a local restaurant.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12246</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:45:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12246</guid></item>
<item><title>Despite few taste genes, honey bees seek out essential nutrients based on floral resources</title><description>Despite having few taste genes, honey bees are fine-tuned to know what minerals the colony may lack and proactively seek out nutrients in conjunction with the season when their floral diet varies.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/02/170209092809.htm</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 06:28:09 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/02/170209092809.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Performance of honey bee colonies under a long-lasting dietary exposure to sub-lethal concentrations of the neonicotinoid insecticide thiacloprid</title><description>AbstractBACKGROUNDSubstantial honey bee colony losses have occurred periodically in the last decades. The drivers for these losses are not fully understood. The influence of pests and pathogens are beyond dispute, but in addition, chronic exposure to sub-lethal concentrations of pesticides has been suggested to affect the performance of honey bee colonies. This study aims to elucidate the potential effects of a chronic exposure to sub-lethal concentrations (one realistic worst-case concentration) of the neonicotinoid thiacloprid to honey bee colonies in a three-year replicated colony feeding study.RESULTSThiacloprid did not significantly affect the colony strength. No differences between treatment and control were observed for the mortality of bees, the infestation with the parasitic mite Varroa destructor and the infection levels of viruses. No colony losses occurred during the overwintering seasons. Furthermore, thiacloprid did not influence the constitutive expression of the immunity related hymenoptaecin gene. However, upregulating of the hymenoptaecin expression as a response to bacterial challenge was less pronounced in exposed bees than in control bees.CONCLUSIONUnder field conditions bee colonies are not adversely affected by a long-lasting exposure to sub-lethal concentrations of thiacloprid. No indications were found that field-realistic and higher doses exerted a biologically significant effect on colony performance.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4547</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 01:50:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4547</guid></item>
<item><title>No effect of Bt Cry1Ie toxin on bacterial diversity in the midgut of the Chinese honey bees, Apis cerana cerana (Hymenoptera, Apidae)</title><description></description><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2017/170131/srep41688/full/srep41688.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/subjects/10.1038/srep41688</guid></item>
<item><title>A beekeeper's perspective on the neonicotinoid ban</title><description>AbstractBees and agrochemicals have a long history. For example, the first volume of IBRA's journal Bee World in 1919 contains mention of poisoning of bees by spraying an orchard with lead arsenate. Bees being insects, it is self-evident that the use of insecticides to control crop pests poses a risk to them. Bee poisoning incidents became a very serious problem in the 1960s and 1970s with spraying of, in particular, oilseed rape with organophosphorus compounds. The introduction of carbamates and then especially synthetic pyrethroids reduced these problems. Data from the Wildlife Incident Investigation Scheme show that in recent years there have been very few poisoning incidents in the United Kingdom that can be attributed to agricultural insecticides. The introduction of neonicotinoid insecticides has, however, been very controversial. Almost as soon as they were introduced in the 1990s, French beekeepers blamed colony losses on imidacloprid used on sunflowers and maize, but restrictions on its use did not lead to a reduction in losses or to a reduction in beekeepers' concerns. Acute pesticide poisoning incidents by neonicotinoids in Germany and Italy in 2008 further sealed their reputation. Despite laboratory evidence showing their harm, field experience remains equivocal, and many commercial beekeepers continue to move their colonies to oilseed rape crops for honey production. The neonicotinoid moratorium has undoubtedly led to the increased use of older insecticides, and the effect of this on bee populations is unknown and unquantified. Many beekeepers are currently confused by the conflicting evidence. © 2016 Society of Chemical Industry</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4489</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 01:38:07 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4489</guid></item>
<item><title>Bee visitation rates to cultivated sunflowers increase with the amount and accessibility of nectar sugars</title><description>AbstractPollinators make foraging decisions based on numerous floral traits, including nectar and pollen rewards, and associated visual and olfactory cues. For insect-pollinated crops, identifying and breeding for attractive floral traits may increase yields. In this study, we examined floral trait variation within cultivated sunflowers and its effects on bee foraging behaviours. Over 2&#160;years, we planted different sunflower inbred lines, including male-fertile and male-sterile lines, and measured nectar volume, nectar sugar concentration and composition, and corolla length. During bloom, we recorded visits by both managed honey bees and wild bees. We then examined consistency in relative nectar production by comparing field results to those from a greenhouse experiment. Sunflower inbred lines varied significantly in all floral traits, including the amount and composition of nectar sugars, and in corolla length. Both wild bee and honey bee visits significantly increased with nectar sugar amount and decreased with corolla length, but appeared unaffected by nectar sugar composition. While wild bees made more visits to sunflowers providing pollen (male-fertile), honey bees preferred plants without pollen (male-sterile). Differences in nectar quantity among greenhouse-grown sunflower lines were similar to those measured in the field, and bumble bees preferentially visited lines with more nectar in greenhouse observations. Our results show that sunflowers with greater quantities of nectar sugar and shorter corollas receive greater pollination services from both managed and wild bees. Selecting for these traits could thus increase sunflower crop yields and provide greater floral resources for bees.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12375</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 02:46:27 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12375</guid></item>
<item><title>Don't 'bee' worried: Researcher says endangered bumblebee populations will rise again</title><description>Bumblebees recently became the first species from the U.S. to be placed on the endangered species list, but an entomologist said bumblebee endangerment is nothing to be bugged about.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170127142923.htm</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 11:29:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170127142923.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Genetic Diversity in Nannotrigona testaceicornis (Hymenoptera: Apidae) Aggregations in Southeastern Brazil</title><description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;The Meliponini, also known as stingless bees, are distributed in tropical and subtropical areas of the world and plays an essential role in pollinating many wild plants and crops These bees can build nests in cavities of trees or walls, underground or in associations with ants or termites; interestingly, these nests are sometimes found in aggregations. In order to assess the genetic diversity and structure in aggregates of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Nannotrigona testaceicornis&lt;/span&gt; (Lepeletier), samples of this species were collected from six aggregations and genetically analyzed for eight specific microsatellite loci. We observed in this analysis that the mean genetic diversity value among aggregations was 0.354, and the mean expected and observed heterozygosity values was 0.414 and 0.283, respectively. The statistically significant &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Fis&lt;/span&gt; value indicated an observed heterozygosity lower than the expected heterozygosity in all loci studied resulting in high homozygosis level in these populations. In addition, the low number of private alleles observed reinforces the absence of structuring that is seen in the aggregates. These results can provide relevant information about genetic diversity in aggregations of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;N. testaceicornis&lt;/span&gt; and contribute to the management and conservation of these bees’ species that are critical for the pollination process.&lt;/span&gt;</description><link>https://academic.oup.com/jinsectscience/article/doi/10.1093/jisesa/iew101/2804976/Genetic-Diversity-in-Nannotrigona-testaceicornis?rss=1</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/jisesa/iew101</guid></item>
<item><title>High Elevation Refugia for Bombus terricola (Hymenoptera: Apidae) Conservation and Wild Bees of the White Mountain National Forest</title><description>&lt;span class="paragraphSection"&gt;Many wild bee species are in global decline, yet much is still unknown about their diversity and contemporary distributions. National parks and forests offer unique areas of refuge important for the conservation of rare and declining species populations. Here we present the results of the first biodiversity survey of the bee fauna in the White Mountain National Forest (WMNF). More than a thousand specimens were collected from pan and sweep samples representing 137 species. Three species were recorded for the first time in New England and an additional seven species were documented for the first time in the state of New Hampshire. Four introduced species were also observed in the specimens collected. A checklist of the species found in the WMNF, as well as those found previously in Strafford County, NH, is included with new state records and introduced species noted as well as a map of collecting locations. Of particular interest was the relatively high abundance of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Bombus terricola&lt;/span&gt; Kirby 1837 found in many of the higher elevation collection sites and the single specimen documented of &lt;span style="font-style:italic;"&gt;Bombus fervidus&lt;/span&gt; (Fabricius 1798). Both of these bumble bee species are known to have declining populations in the northeast and are categorized as vulnerable on the International Union for Conservation of Nature’s Red List.&lt;/span&gt;</description><link>https://academic.oup.com/jinsectscience/article/doi/10.1093/jisesa/iew093/2960099/High-Elevation-Refugia-for-Bombus-terricola?rss=1</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://doi.org/10.1093/jisesa/iew093</guid></item>
<item><title>Neonicotinoids override a parasite exposure impact on&#160;hibernation success of a key bumblebee pollinator</title><description>1. Seasonal adaptations enabling the bridging of periodic challenging abiotic conditions are taxonomically widespread. However, sensitivity to other environmental stresses can be heightened during these periods.2. Several temperate insects with over-wintering strategies play key ecosystem and economic roles, including wild bee pollinators. For example, hibernation survival in temperate bumblebees is crucial, as only new queens of future social colonies over-winter. These bees are also faced with other abiotic and biotic stressors, some of which have been linked to recent pollinator declines, such as exposure to pesticides and parasites.3. Using a fully crossed experiment, the influence of dietary exposure to neonicotinoid insecticides (thiamethoxam and clothianidin) and/or the prevalent bumblebee parasite Crithidia bombi on hibernation survival and hibernation weight change of Bombus terrestris bumblebee queens was investigated.4. Both neonicotinoid and C. bombi exposures reduced hibernation success individually, but no additive or synergistic effects between the stressors were found. Further, effects were asynchronous, with early neonicotinoid effects on hibernation mortality overriding later parasite effects under combined exposures. Neonicotinoid exposure also increased hibernation weight loss of surviving queens.5. Diapause periods, employed by numerous temperate organisms, are likely to be especially vulnerable to environmental stresses, besides the seasonal challenge for which these periods are an adaptation. Thus, diapause requires inclusion during the consideration of the impacts of such stresses. Accordingly, it is demonstrated here that naturally relevant exposures of pesticides and parasites have important detrimental effects on bumblebees during a critical hibernation period, with potential consequences for populations of these key wild pollinators.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12385</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 01:50:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12385</guid></item>
<item><title>A demographic approach to evaluating the impact of stressors on bumble bee colonies</title><description>1. Natural and anthropogenic stressors threaten the sustainability of bumble bees and evaluating their impact is essential to the stewardship of these valuable pollinators. Demographic modelling provides a framework for testing hypotheses about the impacts of stressors, but it has not previously been applied to bumble bees.2. I therefore formulated a demographic model for a bumble bee colony and then quantified the impact of two stressors, pesticide exposure and spider predation, by perturbing it with their known effects.3. By simulating a laboratory exposure of Bombus terrestris L. to dietary imidacloprid (a neonicotinoid insecticide), I tested whether the observed colony decline was explained solely by a toxic effect on the fecundity of the foundress queen. By simulating field observations of B. terricola Kirby, I tested whether predation by crab spiders reduced colony fitness sufficiently to provide an adaptive explanation for avoidance behaviours seen when bumble bees encounter spiders.4. In B. terrestris, a dose-appropriate decrease in fecundity predicted the observed colony decline, which implicates this as a principal mechanism of toxicity. In B. terricola, doubling the rate of spider predation reduced a colony's production of new queens by 11%, which implies that spider avoidance is highly adaptive.5. These analyses illustrate the utility of demographic modelling for quantifying the impacts of stressors on bumble bees. In the future, models of this type could be used to investigate a wider range of stressors and to produce thereby knowledge and tools useful for safeguarding bumble bees and the pollination services that they provide.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12376</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 08:00:27 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12376</guid></item>
<item><title>Pitching in: Biologists study development of division of labor among bees</title><description>Biologists tested a variation of the reproductive ground plan hypothesis in solitary, ground-nesting bees of south central Washington State. Their findings could shed light on development of division of labor in social bees.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117192654.htm</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 16:26:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117192654.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Sweat bees on hot chillies: Native bees thrive in traditional farming, securing good yield</title><description>Farming doesn't always have to be harmful to bees: Even though farmers on the Mexican peninsula of Yucatan traditionally slash-and-burn forest to create small fields, this practice can be beneficial to sweat bees by creating attractive habitats. The farmers profit also since they depend on bees to pollinate their habanero chillies.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117140203.htm</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 11:02:03 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117140203.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Australia's most lethal? Insects pose biggest health threat, analysis shows</title><description>An Australian-first national analysis of 13 years' data on bites and stings from venomous creatures reveals Australia's towns and cities are a hot-spot for encounters. The stereotype-busting research also shows that of all Australia's venomous creatures, it is bees and other insects -- not snakes, spiders, or jellyfish -- that pose the biggest public health threat.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117101430.htm</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 07:14:30 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170117101430.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Common crop chemical leaves bees susceptible to deadly viruses</title><description>A chemical that is thought to be safe and is, therefore, widely used on crops -- such as almonds, wine grapes and tree fruits -- to boost the performance of pesticides, makes honey bee larvae significantly more susceptible to a deadly virus, according to researchers.</description><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170116092933.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 06:29:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2017/01/170116092933.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Pollen nutrients better explain bumblebee colony development than pollen diversity</title><description>AbstractBumblebees are valuable pollinators of numerous wild and cultivated plants. They can forage on variable pollen resources. As some pollen species lack particular nutrients or have global low nutritional quality, it has been suggested that bumblebees mix their pollen incomes to ensure a global balanced diet. The hypothesis that a mixed pollen diet better supports bumblebee colony development than a single pollen diet has been poorly explored.We compared the impact of mono-, di- and trifloral diets on microcolony development of Bombus terrestris using three pollen resources with different nutrient contents (Cytisus scoparius, Erica sp. and Sorbus aucuparia) as well as their mixes. Nine parameters (e.g. pollen efficacy: total weight of larvae/total weight of pollen collection) were used to compare the microcolony performances. Moreover, we measured the influence of the pollen diversity and nutritional composition on relevant parameters.We showed that microcolonies can potentially better develop on mixed pollen diets, but single pollen diet can also be as good as mixed pollen diet. Moreover, the sterol concentration appeared as a key factor to establish the impact of a pollen diet on the bumblebee colony development.This study reveals that diverse pollen diet does not necessary equate with good colony development and supports the importance of selecting floral resources by considering their nutrient contents for bee conservation management.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Ficad.12213</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 22:00:32 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Ficad.12213</guid></item>
<item><title>The cephalic labial gland secretions of two socially parasitic bumblebees Bombus hyperboreus (Alpinobombus) and Bombus inexspectatus (Thoracobombus) question their inquiline strategy</title><description>AbstractSocial parasitic Hymenopterans have evolved morphological, chemical, and behavioral adaptations to overcome the sophisticated recognition and defense systems of their social host to invade host nests and exploit their worker force. In bumblebees, social parasitism appeared in at least 3 subgenera independently: in the subgenus Psithyrus consisting entirely of parasitic species, in the subgenus Alpinobombus with Bombus hyperboreus, and in the subgenus Thoracobombus with B. inexspectatus. Cuckoo bumblebee males utilize species-specific cephalic labial gland secretions for mating purposes that can impact their inquiline strategy. We performed cephalic labial gland secretions in B. hyperboreus, B. inexspectatus and their hosts. Males of both parasitic species exhibited high species specific levels of cephalic gland secretions, including different main compounds. Our results showed no chemical mimicry in the cephalic gland secretions between inquilines and their host and we did not identify the repellent compounds already known in other cuckoo bumblebees.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12408</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 23:10:29 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12408</guid></item>
<item><title>The adverse impact of the neonicotinoid seed treatment ban on crop protection in oilseed rape in the UK</title><description>AbstractThis paper describes the consequences of the ban on neonicotinoid seed treatments on pest management in oilseed rape. Since the ban was implemented in December 2013, there have been serious crop losses in 2014, 2015 and 2016 due to cabbage stem flea beetles, Psylliodes chrysocephala, and aphids, Myzus persicae, which have developed resistance to the alternative pyrethroid sprays that were employed to control them. This has resulted in increased crop losses, decreased yields, and a substantial decrease in the area grown, leading to fewer flowering crops available in the spring, especially in the eastern region of the UK. This is likely to have an adverse effect on bees locally.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4511</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 23:25:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1002%2Fps.4511</guid></item>
<item><title>Is non-host pollen suitable for generalist bumblebees?</title><description>AbstractCurrent evidence suggests that pollen is both chemically and structurally protected. Despite increasing interest in studying bee–flower networks, the constraints for bee development related to pollen nutritional content, toxicity and digestibility as well as their role in the shaping of bee–flower interactions have been poorly studied. In this study we combined bioassays of the generalist bee Bombus terrestris on pollen of Cirsium, Trifolium, Salix, and Cistus genera with an assessment of nutritional content, toxicity, and digestibility of pollen. Microcolonies showed significant differences in their development, non-host pollen of Cirsium being the most unfavorable. This pollen was characterized by the presence of quite rare δ7-sterols and a low digestibility. Cirsium consumption seemed increase syrup collection, which is probably related to a detoxification mixing behavior. These results strongly suggest that pollen traits may act as drivers of plant selection by bees and partly explain why Asteraceae pollen is rare in bee generalist diet.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12410</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 19:46:39 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12410</guid></item>
<item><title>Seasonality of salt foraging in honey bees (Apis mellifera)</title><description>1. Honey bees (Apis mellifera) prefer foraging at compound-rich, ‘dirty’, water sources over clean water sources. As a honey bee's main floral diet only contains trace amounts of micronutrients&#160;–&#160;likely not enough to sustain an entire colony&#160;–&#160;it was hypothesised that honey bees forage in dirty water for physiologically essential minerals that their floral diet, and thus the colony, may lack.2. While there are many studies regarding macronutrient requirements of honey bees, few investigate micronutrient needs. For this study, from 2013 to 2015, a series of preference assays were conducted in both summer and autumn.3. During all field seasons, honey bees exhibited a strong preference for sodium in comparison to deionised water. There was, however, a notable switch in preferences for other minerals between seasons.4. Calcium, magnesium, and potassium&#160;–&#160;three minerals most commonly found in pollen&#160;–&#160;were preferred in autumn when pollen was scarce, but were avoided in summer when pollen was abundant. Thus, as floral resources change in distribution and abundance, honey bees similarly change their water-foraging preferences.5. Our data suggest that, although they are generalists with relatively few gustatory receptor genes, honey bee foragers are fine-tuned to search for micronutrients. This ability likely helps the foragers in their search for a balanced diet for the colony as a whole.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12375</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 23:15:27 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Feen.12375</guid></item>
<item><title>Methoprene does not affect juvenile hormone titers in honey bee (Apis mellifera) workers</title><description>AbstractMethoprene, a juvenile hormone (JH) analog, is a widely used insecticide that also accelerates behavioral development in honey bees (Apis mellifera). JH regulates the transition from nursing to foraging in adult worker bees, and treatment with JH or methoprene have both been shown to induce precocious foraging. To determine how methoprene changes honey bee behavior, we compared JH titers of methoprene-treated and untreated bees. Behavioral observations confirmed that methoprene treatment significantly increased the number of precocious foragers in 3 out of 4 colonies. In only 1 out of 4 colonies, however, was there a significant difference in JH titers between the methoprene-treated and control bees. Further, in all 4 colonies, there was no significant differences in JH titers between precocious and normal-aged foragers. These results suggest that methoprene did not directly affect the endogenous JH secreted by corpora allata. Because methoprene caused early foraging without changing workers’ JH titers, we conclude that methoprene most likely acts directly on the JH receptors as a substitute for JH.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12411</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 04:38:56 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12411</guid></item>
<item><title>Landscape spatial configuration is a key driver of wild bee demographics</title><description>AbstractThe majority of studies investigating the effects of landscape composition and configuration on bee populations have been conducted in regions of intensive agricultural production, ignoring regions which are dominated by seminatural habitats, such as the islands of the Aegean Archipelago. In addition, research so far has focused on the landscape impacts on bees sampled in cropped fields while the landscape effects on bees inhabiting seminatural habitats are understudied. Here, we investigate the impact of the landscape on wild bee assemblages in 66 phryganic (low scrubland) communities on 8 Aegean islands. We computed landscape metrics (total area and total perimeter–area ratio) in 4 concentric circles (250, 500, 750, and 1000 m) around the center of each bee sampling site including 3 habitat groups (namely phrygana, cultivated land, and natural forests). We further measured the local flower cover in 25 quadrats distributed randomly at the center of each sampling site. We found that the landscape scale is more important than the local scale in shaping abundance and species richness of bees. Furthermore, habitat configuration was more important than the total area of habitats, probably because it affects bees’ movement across the landscape. Phrygana and natural forests had a positive effect on bee demographics, while cultivated land had a negative effect. This demonstrates that phryganic specialists drive bee assemblages in these seminatural landscapes. This finding, together with the shown importance of landscape scale, should be considered for the management of wild bees with special emphasis placed on the spatial configuration of seminatural habitats.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12383</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 16:45:24 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12383</guid></item>
<item><title>A different gut microbial community between larvae and adults of a wild bumblebee nest (Bombus pascuorum)</title><description>AbstractAlthough the gut microbial communities in adult bumblebees and their associated functionalities are widely studied, descriptive data on the larval gut microbiota are still limited. The gut microbiota of a fully sampled wild Bombus pascuorum nest has been characterized, using the multiplexed Illumina MiSeq 16S ribosomal RNA amplicon sequencing technique. The nesters and foragers inhabiting the same nest showed the typical core bacterial sequences and only marginal differences in their characterized gut microbiota. The gut microbial communities within the adult and larval specimens differed strongly, as the typical core gut bacteria in the adult bumblebees are absent in the larval bumblebees. The bacterial communities within the larval gut are dominated by bacterial phylotypes of Enterobacteriaceae and Lactobacillaceae, supplemented with genera belonging to Corynebacteriales and Bacillales. The function of this larval gut microbiota, being different from the adult, remains to be determined.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12381</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:11:05 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12381</guid></item>
<item><title>Bumblebees depend on ericaceous species to survive in temperate heathlands</title><description>AbstractBumblebees are the predominant wild pollinators for many plant species in temperate regions. A bumblebee colony requires pollen and nectar throughout its lifetime, but degraded and fragmented habitats may have gaps in the temporal and spatial continuity of floral resources.Heathlands are open biotopes that provide favourable habitat for bumblebees like Bombus jonellus, a declining species in Belgium. In heathlands, ericaceous species are the main plants that provide pollen and nectar for bumblebees. Although the nectar composition of ericaceous species has been previously studied, data on pollen composition remain scarce.We examined bumblebee diets (composition of their pollen loads) in Belgian heathlands over the course of a colony lifetime to assess the fidelity of bumblebees for ericaceous species. We compared nutritional values by investigating the chemical composition (amino acids, polypeptides and sterols) of the pollen of the ericaceous and dominant non-ericaceous species present in pollen loads. No relationship was detected between the abundance of a particular plant species in bumblebee loads and its pollen composition.The successive flowering periods and the nutritional quality of pollen of ericaceous species offer valuable resources for bumblebees. Ericaceous species represent a large part of bumblebee diets in heathlands, especially in early spring and late summer when the diversity of other flowering species was low.Bumblebee pollen loads also contained non-ericaceous flowering species that grow outside heathlands. Thus, land planning must incorporate conservation strategies for the different elements of the landscape matrix, including heathlands, peatlands, meadows and margins.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Ficad.12201</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 23:10:24 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Ficad.12201</guid></item>
<item><title>Dependence of Asian honeybee on deciduous woody plants for pollen resource during spring to mid-summer in northern Japan</title><description>AbstractApis cerana japonica Radoszkowski, endemic to Japan, is known to be one of the most important pollinators for wild plants and crops, such as buckwheat, in cool to warm temperate Japan. To determine the degree of dependence of A. cerana japonica on forest resources, we analyzed pollen brought back to nests in a typical “Satoyama” landscape with relatively high deciduous forest coverage in northern Japan. We divided the landscape elements of the study area into three types: deciduous forest, conifer plantation and open land according to landcover digital data, and each pollen taxon was assigned to one of these three types of landscape elements. We collected total pollen loads of 15.75 g (total of colonies A and B) in May (spring), 1.57 g (total of colonies A and C) in June (early summer), 19.03 g (total of colonies A, B and C) in July (mid-summer) and 45.61 g (total of colonies A, B and D) in September (autumn). Deciduous forests are the most important foraging habitats for A. cerana japonica in the “Satoyama” landscape especially from spring to mid-summer when mass flowering of tall trees and shrubs species provides rich floral resources for developing bee colonies. On the other hand, the bees frequently foraged from herbaceous plant species in autumn when flowering of tree species reduces and herbaceous plant species have flowering peaks. In turn, the bees provide pollination services to a number of wild flowers blooming in various forest layers ranging from the canopy to the understory layer.Deciduous forests are the most important foraging habitats for Apis cerana japonica in the Satoyama landscape especially from spring to mid-summer when mass flowering of tall trees and shrubs species provide rich floral resources for developing bee colonies. Apis c. japonica provides pollination services to a number of wild flowers blooming in various forest layers ranging from the canopy to the understory layer.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12228</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 19:15:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12228</guid></item>
<item><title>Expression of key components of the RNAi machinery are suppressed in Apis mellifera that suffer a high virus infection</title><description>AbstractViruses are one of the major threats for honeybees and until now more than 20 different viruses have been discovered. Viruses and their hosts are engaged in a continuous arms race in which viral defense mechanisms drive the adaptive evolution of host immune genes, which in turn results in counter-adaptations of the viral immune antagonists. The honeybee immune responses to non-viral pathogens have been extensively studied, but little is known about the antiviral responses. Recent evidence suggests that the main mechanism of antiviral defense in insects is the RNA interference (RNAi) pathway. Furthermore, there is evidence that some viruses suppress this RNAi pathway in order to evade antiviral immunity. In the present study, we test this hypothesis by comparing the gene expression levels of some key components of the RNAi response of honeybees that were naturally infected with at least five viruses with those who were infected with only two or three viruses using a colorimetric microarray developed in-house, called BeeClinic, and subsequently confirmed by quantitative reverse-transcription–polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Our results show that key components of the RNAi pathway are indeed downregulated in highly infected bees. We were able to show that high virus loads suppress key RNAi components, which results in a counteraction of the host RNAi antiviral defense. As the RNAi is a primary defense against viruses, these findings shed new light on pathogen–host interactions and can help mitigate escalating colony losses worldwide.We could show that high virus loads suppress key RNAi components, which results in a counteraction of the host RNAi antiviral defence. As the RNAi is a primary defence against viruses, these findings shed new light on the pathogen host interactions and can help to mitigate escalating colony losses worldwide.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12227</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 22:20:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12227</guid></item>
<item><title>Origins and implications of apid bees (Hymentopera: Apidae) in French Polynesia</title><description>AbstractIsland plant–pollinator networks are typically simpler than their continental counterparts and this can make them less resilient to disturbance from exotic species. French Polynesia has a very low diversity of bees, but their status as either native or introduced species has been largely speculative. We combine previous studies with new DNA sequence data to show that 11 bee species have now been recorded for French Polynesia. Haplotype variation at the ‘barcode’ region of the mitochondrial gene cytochrome c oxidase subunit I (COI) for four of these species, Ceratina dentipes Freise, Xylocopa sonorina Smith, Braunsapis puangensis (Cockerell) and Amegilla pulchra (Smith), indicates that they all represent very recent introductions. Apis mellifera Linnaeus was a purposefully introduced species, and four megachilid species probably arrived due to human-aided dispersal through maritime activities in the Pacific. The two remaining bee species, an unidentified partial specimen of a halictid bee and the colletid bee Hylaeus (P.) tuamotuensis Michener, are collectively known from only four specimens collected in the 1930s and their provenance is uncertain. French Polynesia therefore comprises a region where recently introduced bee species greatly overwhelm any possible native bee fauna. These introductions are likely to have major ecosystem impacts, including disruptions of existing plant–pollinator networks and facilitating the spread of weedy plant species, as well as positive impacts for agriculture. Future biosecurity initiatives need to consider these potential impacts and the likely routes of dispersal to effectively control any further unintended introductions.Using mitochondrial DNA we show that all bee species of the family Apidae in French Polynesia are introduced. Based on our understanding of the remaining known species, this result suggests that bees are not endemic to the island group. This has implications for the genesis of biodiversity on these islands given the importance of bees as pollinators, but these introduced species may be of utility in food production.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12230</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 18:50:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fens.12230</guid></item>
<item><title>Population structuring of the ubiquitous stingless bee Tetragonisca angustula in southern Brazil as revealed by microsatellite and mitochondrial markers</title><description>AbstractTetragonisca angustula is one of the most widespread stingless bees in the Neotropics. This species swarms frequently and is extremely successful in urban environments. In addition, it is one of the most popular stingless bee species for beekeeping in Latin America, so nest transportation and trading is common. Nest transportation can change the genetic structure of the host population, reducing inbreeding and increasing homogenization. Here, we evaluate the genetic structure of 17 geographic populations of T. angustula in southern Brazil to quantify the level of genetic differentiation between populations. Analyses were conducted on partially sequenced mitochondrial genes and 11 microsatellite loci of 1002 workers from 457 sites distributed on the mainland and on 3 islands. Our results show that T. angustula populations are highly differentiated as demonstrated by mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA) and microsatellite markers. Of 73 haplotypes, 67 were population-specific. MtDNA diversity was low in 9 populations but microsatellite diversity was moderate to high in all populations. Microsatellite data suggest 10 genetic clusters and low level of gene flow throughout the studied area. However, physical barriers, such as rivers and mountain ranges, or the presence or absence of forest appear to be unrelated to population clusters. Factors such as low dispersal, different ecological conditions, and isolation by distance are most likely shaping the population structure of this species. Thus far, nest transportation has not influenced the general population structure in the studied area. However, due to the genetic structure we found, we recommend that nest transportation should only occur within and between populations that are genetically similar.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12371</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 21:26:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12371</guid></item>
<item><title>No evidence that DNA methylation is associated with the regulation of fertility in the adult honey bee Apis mellifera (Hymenoptera: Apidae) worker ovary</title><description>AbstractEpigenetic modifications, mediated by DNA methylation, are involved in caste differentiation between queen and worker honey bees, Apis mellifera. This study uses methylation sensitive amplified fragment length polymorphism (MS-AFLP) to investigate whether genome-wide DNA methylation is implicated in the regulation of honey bee worker sterility and whether CO2 narcosis, which suppresses ovary activation in queenless workers, influences DNA methylation. Queenless workers were divided into control and experimental (CO2 narcosis) cages. We compared MS-AFLP patterns in CO2-treated and non-treated workers with and without activated ovaries at 4 h, 2  and 7 days after treatment. While there was evidence of DNA methylation in all samples, there was no detectable difference in genome-wide methylation patterns between any treatment comparisons. This suggests that mechanisms that regulate worker sterility in the adult honey bee worker are not related to genome-wide methylation, and that CO2 narcosis does not significantly affect DNA methylation patterns in the worker ovary. However, because DNA methylation is sparse in the honey bee, and because MS-AFLP detects only a proportion of methylated sites, it remains possible that a subset of genes that are responsible for the regulation of worker sterility are differentially methylated, but that we failed to pick these up in our genome-wide scan.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Faen.12218</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 23:21:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Faen.12218</guid></item>
<item><title>Potential pollination maintenance by an exotic allodapine bee under climate change scenarios in the Indo-Pacific region</title><description>AbstractRecent studies suggest an alarming decline in pollinators across many regions of the world due to multiple factors. One potential factor is climate change, which poses both direct and indirect threats to pollinator populations. To help ameliorate the impact of declining populations on the function of ecological and agricultural systems, there is a need to identify species that may adapt to limit the magnitude of this pollination deficit. The South West Pacific has a highly depauperate endemic bee diversity and numerous non-indigenous species, including honeybees. One allodapine bee, Braunsapis puangensis, has been accidentally introduced to Fiji where it has rapidly spread across multiple islands and become locally abundant. It is a long-tongued bee, unaffected by honeybee pathogens, and has the potential to become an important crop pollinator. Here, we model the distribution of this species under different climate scenarios to determine how it is likely to respond to future climate change. We show that its distribution is unlikely to contract, but potentially expand with climate warming. These scenarios therefore indicate that the plasticity in B.&#160;puangensis populations may allow it to represent an important crop pollinator in this region should honeybee populations decline.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12337</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 01:30:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12337</guid></item>
<item><title>Performance of honeybee colonies located in neonicotinoid-treated and untreated cornfields in Quebec</title><description>AbstractTwenty-two honeybee (Apis mellifera) colonies were placed in four different cornfield areas in order to study the potential in&#160;situ effects of seed-coated systemic neonicotinoid pesticides used in cornfields (Zea mays spp) on honeybee health. Two apiaries were located in two independent neonicotinoid-treated cornfield areas and two others in two independent untreated cornfield areas used as controls. These experimental hives were extensively monitored for their performance and health traits over a period of one year. Trapped pollen was collected and microscopically identified to define the visited flowers and the amount of corn pollen collected by bees. Liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry was performed to detect pesticide residues in honeybee foragers and trapped pollen. Honeybee colonies located in neonicotinoid-treated cornfields expressed significantly higher varroa mite loads than those in untreated cornfields. However, brood production and colony weight were less disturbed by the treatment factor. Sublethal doses of neonicotinoids were detected in the trapped corn pollen and none in bee foragers. Overall, our results show that forager bees collected 20% of corn pollen containing variable concentrations of neonicotinoids. Colonies located in treated cornfields expressed higher varroa loads and long-term mortality than those in untreated cornfields. On the other hand, no significant differences were observed regarding the brood production and colony weight.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12336</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 02:41:20 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Fjen.12336</guid></item>
<item><title>Flight range of the Australian stingless bee Tetragonula carbonaria (Hymenoptera: Apidae)</title><description>AbstractBees are key pollinators in both natural and agricultural environments throughout the world. Estimates of the typical distance from their nest that bees will fly to forage are useful when planning their deployment in commercial pollination or ecosystem management. Stingless bees (Meliponini) are social bees that live in colonies comprising a queen and many workers. They pollinate several key tropical crops and can be housed and transported in hives. Thus, there is increasing interest in their use as managed pollinators in regions where they occur naturally, including Australia. Here, we use a mark and release method to estimate the homing range of the most commonly propagated species of Australian stingless bee, Tetragonula carbonaria (Smith), where homing range serves as a proxy for foraging flight range. We find the typical and maximum homing range of T. carbonaria to be 333 and 712 m, respectively. This range is less than that of the most commonly used commercial pollinator, the honey bee Apis mellifera Linnaeus, which we argue confers both advantages and disadvantages on T. carbonaria as an alternative crop pollinator.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Faen.12206</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 06:05:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2Faen.12206</guid></item>
<item><title>Distribution and variability of deformed wing virus of honeybees (Apis mellifera) in the Middle East and North Africa</title><description>AbstractThree hundred and eleven honeybee samples from 12 countries in the Middle East and North Africa (MENA) (Jordan, Lebanon, Syria, Iraq, Egypt, Libya, Tunisia, Algeria, Morocco, Yemen, Palestine, and Sudan) were analyzed for the presence of deformed wing virus (DWV). The prevalence of DWV throughout the MENA region was pervasive, but variable. The highest prevalence was found in Lebanon and Syria, with prevalence dropping in Palestine, Jordan, and Egypt before increasing slightly moving westwards to Algeria and Morocco Phylogenetic analysis of a 194 nucleotide section of the DWV Lp gene did not identify any significant phylogenetic resolution among the samples, although the sequences did show consistent regional clustering, including an interesting geographic gradient from Morocco through North Africa to Jordan and Syria. The sequences revealed several clear variability hotspots in the deduced amino acid sequence, which furthermore showed some patterns of regional identity. Furthermore, the sequence variants from the Middle East and North Africa appear more numerous and diverse than those from Europe.</description><link>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12277</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 23:14:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/resolve/doi?DOI=10.1111%2F1744-7917.12277</guid></item></channel></rss>
