<!DOCTYPE HTML PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01//EN"
   "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/strict.dtd">
<html lang="en">
<head>
    <meta http-equiv="Content-Type" content="text/html; charset=ISO-8859-1">
    <meta name="robots" content="noindex,nofollow,noarchive">
    <link rel="stylesheet" href="style.css" type="text/css">
    <title>rawdog</title>
</head>
<body id="rawdog">
<div id="header">
<h1>rawdog</h1>
</div>
<div id="items">
<item><title>Better corn in our future: Meaningful part of maize genome identified: Using a new genetic mapping technique researchers have shown that a small percentage of the entire maize genome is responsible for almost half of a plant's trait diversity.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516212713.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 18:27:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516212713.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Do germs cause type 1 diabetes?: Germs could play a role in the development of type 1 diabetes by triggering the body's immune system to destroy the cells that produce insulin, new research suggests.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516212653.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 18:26:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516212653.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Researchers find new bee species in NH - Eagle-Tribune: <table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align: top;"><tr><td align="center" valign="top" width="80"><font style="font-size: 85%; font-family: arial,sans-serif;"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFhFoO4G27rFJ2m-GgQT1VfOIZQfQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.eagletribune.com/news/new_hampshire/researchers-find-new-bee-species-in-nh/article_e648124a-1a56-5c80-9beb-4968c88174f6.html"><img alt="" border="1" height="80" src="https://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcTBSCP2NYifl8b8Ze5hMwRb-Nw9qcmNvNcfFzmj3GXCSU-ZIQfQmPHVd7lo5sTAndP8jYqO01s" width="80" /><br /><font size="-2">Eagle-Tribune</font></a></font></td><td class="j" valign="top"><font style="font-size: 85%; font-family: arial,sans-serif;"><br /><div style="padding-top: 0.8em;"><img alt="" height="1" width="1" /></div><div class="lh"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFhFoO4G27rFJ2m-GgQT1VfOIZQfQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.eagletribune.com/news/new_hampshire/researchers-find-new-bee-species-in-nh/article_e648124a-1a56-5c80-9beb-4968c88174f6.html"><b>Researchers find new bee species in NH</b></a><br /><font size="-1"><b><font color="#6f6f6f">Eagle-Tribune</font></b></font><br /><font size="-1">DURHAM, N.H. &#8212; Researchers at the New Hampshire Agricultural Experiment Station &#8212; located at the University of New Hampshire &#8212; are buzzing about a recently completed study that explores the state's <b>native bee</b> population. Sandra Rehan, an <b>...</b></font><br /><font size="-1"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGZPUb7GvkKS2wB7o7ChQg6ywqm-g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.dispatchtribunal.com/we-must-save-wild-bees-let-it-bee-campaign-launched/29150/">We must save wild bees; &quot;Let It Bee&quot; campaign launched</a><font color="#6f6f6f" size="-1">Dispatch Tribunal</font></font><br /><font size="-1"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNEaHz1XsWdpwjMOl9x2GAp2ys_eeA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://nhv.us/content/16056188-let-it-bee-campaign-urges-canadians-help-protecting-bees">'Let It Bee': Campaign urges Canadians to Help in Protecting Bees</a><font color="#6f6f6f" size="-1">NH Voice</font></font><br /><font size="-1"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFP0ILCPJdd9ofC1MKe8M8mgjEt8Q&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.chroniclejournal.com/news/local/humans-must-save-wild-bees-campaign/article_1c5ff2a6-1aa2-11e6-8b7a-0bf26601d8a6.html">Humans must save wild bees: campaign</a><font color="#6f6f6f" size="-1">The Chronicle Journal</font></font><br /><font class="p" size="-1"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNGRY4afOj9TAD05YyAEwWTqNcYjVA&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.cantechletter.com/2016/05/let-bee-campaign-aims-save-canadas-bees/">Cantech Letter</a>&nbsp;-<a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFglD0KB4ngLds8sQPfcsL71SNQdQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.themarshalltown.com/2016/05/16/scientists-complete-first-assessment-of-states-bees/">The Marshalltown</a></font><br /><font class="p" size="-1"><a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?ncl=dMa8CsTKlWFZZbMrUNQGTOyeg20ZM&amp;authuser=0&amp;ned=us"><b>all 13 news articles&nbsp;&raquo;</b></a></font></div></font></td></tr></table></title><link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFhFoO4G27rFJ2m-GgQT1VfOIZQfQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.eagletribune.com/news/new_hampshire/researchers-find-new-bee-species-in-nh/article_e648124a-1a56-5c80-9beb-4968c88174f6.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNFhFoO4G27rFJ2m-GgQT1VfOIZQfQ&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;cid=52779106947809&amp;ei=LIc6V8CsBoWCwQHBoL7ACA&amp;url=http://www.eagletribune.com/news/new_hampshire/researchers-find-new-bee-species-in-nh/article_e648124a-1a56-5c80-9beb-4968c88174f6.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Untreated sleep apnea may be related to melanoma aggressiveness: Untreated severe obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is associated with increased aggressiveness of malignant cutaneous melanoma, according to the first multicenter prospective study on the relationship between sleep-disordered breathing (apnea or hypopnea) and cancer.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181459.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:14:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181459.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Lead pollution reveals the ancient history of Naples: Almost two thousand years after the eruption of Vesuvius that destroyed Pompeii and Herculaneum, certain periods of the history of Naples have just been reconstructed. Until now, historians and archaeologists had wondered about the impact of this volcanic eruption on the Aqua Augusta aqueduct which supplied Naples and neighboring cities with water. Recent geochemical analyses have made it possible to directly link the lead in the water pipes of the period with that trapped in the sediments of the old port of Naples.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181334.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:13:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181334.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New implantable VAD for severe heart failure in kids shows encouraging results in sheep: First-Ever Implantable VAD for Small Children May Be a Breakthrough for the Management of Pediatric Heart Failure, According to Presentation at 96th AATS Annual Meeting</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181332.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:13:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181332.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Increasing survival in soft tissue sarcoma patients with lung metastases undergoing resection: Up to 50% of patients with soft tissue sarcoma (STS) develop lung metastases. Effective systemic therapies for metastatic STS are currently limited; when possible, surgical removal of the lung metastases (known as pulmonary metastasectomy, PM) is the preferred treatment. However, guidelines for the performance of PM for STS do not exist and decisions to operate are often made on an individual basis.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181330.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:13:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181330.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Cancer risk perception could lead to adverse health outcomes among women: According to recent studies, the US has a disadvantage in women's life expectancy compared to peer countries despite high rates of health screenings. Researchers have examined the perceptions of risk among females and found that minority and less educated women believe that breast cancer, rather than heart disease, is the more common killer. They recommend health care providers incorporate healthier lifestyle strategies for heart disease with messages for improved breast health.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181248.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181248.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Children, youth take longer to fully recover from concussion: The findings indicate that those in the age group of eight and 16 are not only vulnerable to concussions, but because their brain is still developing, they are neurologically more fragile than adults for performing tasks that require cognitive motor integration following a concussion.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181223.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181223.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Biodiversity protects fish from climate change: Fish provide protein to billions of people and are an especially critical food source in the developing world. Today marine biologists confirmed a key factor that could help them thrive through the coming decades: biodiversity. Communities with more fish species are more productive and more resilient to rising temperatures and temperature swings, according to a new study.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181221.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181221.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New packaging advances veggie freshness: New advances in packaging can help produce stay fresh longer. A research team focused on onions, one of the highest-volume vegetables sold worldwide. The team's results show that improvements can enhance the safety and improve the quality of the ubiquitous vegetable.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181219.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181219.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Slips of the lip stay all in the family: Dogs included, but not the cat: It's happened to many of us: While looking at someone you know very well, you blurt out the wrong name. The name you blurt is not just any old name, though, says new research from Duke University that finds 'misnaming' follows predictable patterns.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181217.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181217.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Minimally invasive tendon repair technique supports knee movement sooner after surgery: Researchers have found that suture anchors, a less-invasive tendon repair technique, responded better to strength-testing after the surgery, supporting more movement in the knee earlier in the recovery process.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181213.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181213.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Teamwork enables bacterial survival: Researchers have found that two strains of E. coli bacteria, each resistant to one antibiotic, can protect each other in an environment where both drugs are present.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181211.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:12:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181211.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Scientists create novel 'liquid wire' material inspired by spiders' capture silk: Why doesn't a spider's web sag in the wind or catapult flies back out like a trampoline? The answer, according to scientists, lies in the physics behind a 'hybrid' material produced by spiders for their webs.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181037.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181037.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Second gene modifies effect of mutation in a dog model of ALS: Canine Degenerative Myelopathy (DM) is a neurodegenerative disease in dogs with similarities to ALS in humans. Scientists have discovered a modifier gene that affects the risk of developing DM in Pembroke Welsh Corgis (PWC).</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181035.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181035.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Trojan horses for hospital bugs: Staphylococcus aureus usually is a formidable bacterial pathogen. Sometimes, however, weakened forms are found in the blood of patients. Researchers have now identified one mutation responsible for that phenomenon.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181030.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181030.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Risk factors identified for readmission to hospital following esophagectomy: Researchers have identified risk factors for unplanned readmissions following esophageal resection. The results of their new study provide complete follow-up data for all patients undergoing esophagectomy at a high volume center over a one-year period in order to identify risk factors associated with unplanned readmissions.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181027.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181027.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Curtailing global warming with bioengineering? Iron fertilization won't work in much of Pacific: Over the past half-million years, the equatorial Pacific Ocean has seen five spikes in the amount of iron-laden dust blown in from the continents. In theory, those bursts should have turbo-charged the growth of the ocean's carbon-capturing algae -- algae need iron to grow -- but a new study shows that the excess iron had little to no effect.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181020.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181020.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Mom's voice activates many different regions in children's brains, study shows: A far wider swath of brain areas is activated when children hear their mothers than when they hear other voices, and this brain response predicts a child's social communication ability, a new study finds.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181017.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 15:10:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516181017.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Zoetis launching new doggy med for noise-related anxiety: Fido and Spot may not have to cower under the bed this summer when fireworks and thunderstorms hit, thanks to the first prescription veterinary medicine for treating anxiety over loud noises&#8212;a widespread problem that causes property destruction, terrified dogs running away and even life-threatening injuries or euthanasia for some.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-zoetis-doggy-med-noise-related-anxiety.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 14:11:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-zoetis-doggy-med-noise-related-anxiety.html</guid></item>
<item><title>New answer to why Earth's atmosphere became oxygenated: Earth scientists are offering a new answer to the long-standing question of how our planet acquired its oxygenated atmosphere. Based on a new model that draws from research in diverse fields including petrology, geodynamics, volcanology and geochemistry, the team's findings suggest that the rise of oxygen in Earth's atmosphere was an inevitable consequence of the formation of continents in the presence of life and plate tectonics.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151935.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:19:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151935.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New cancer immunotherapy approach combines tumor fighting power with fewer side effects, study shows: Basic research into the dual nature of certain immune system cells has set the stage for a new approach to cancer immunotherapy that avoids some of the shortcomings associated with other methods, scientists report in a new study.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151926.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:19:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151926.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>The 'Echoverse': New way to think about brand-consumer interactions: Most studies of the interactions between companies and consumers look at one piece of the puzzle: Advertising or social media or news coverage or 'consumer sentiment' as measured in surveys. A new study examines how messages about brands across various channels interact in a complex set of feedback loops the authors call the 'echoverse.' And the study offers advice for managers on navigating this new complex media world.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151619.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:16:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151619.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Converting cells to burn fat, not store it: Researchers have uncovered a new molecular pathway for stimulating the body to burn fat -- a discovery that could help fight obesity, diabetes and cardiovascular disease.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151615.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:16:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151615.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Methionine could be key to improving pregnancy rate in dairy cattle: Adding methionine to the diets of Holstein cows during the prepartum and postpartum periods may impact the preimplantation embryo in a way that enhances its capacity for survival, research indicates.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151612.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:16:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151612.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Monthly resident handoff of patients may increase risk of dying: Transitions in care that occur when medical residents leave a clinical rotation and turn their patients' care over to another resident is associated with increased mortality, according to new research.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151608.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:16:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151608.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>ICUs strained by increased volume and a near doubling of opioid-related deaths: ICU admissions related to opioid overdoses are steadily increasing, and opioid overdose-related ICU deaths have nearly doubled since 2009. New research shows the strain America's opioid crisis is putting on ICUs and the critical care teams who care for these patients and calls attention to efforts needed to meet the demands of this expanding population.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151606.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 12:16:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516151606.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Technique improves efficacy of fuel cells: Fuel cells, which generate electricity from chemical reactions without harmful emissions, have the potential to power everything from cars to portable electronics, and could be cleaner and more efficient than combustion engines.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135841.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:58:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135841.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Cooling cows efficiently with water spray: Dairies use intermittent sprinkler systems to cool cows in warm weather, but little experimental work has been done to determine how much water is needed to achieve beneficial effects. A group of dairy scientists to examine the effects of using low-flow sprinkler systems that cut water use for this purpose by nearly 75 percent.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135808.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:58:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135808.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Metals released by burning fuel oil may damage children's developing lungs: A new study investigating the health impact of the chemical components of air pollution is reporting that two metals, nickel and vanadium (Ni and V), may be damaging to the developing lungs of children.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135805.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:58:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516135805.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Left uncontrolled, weeds would cost billions in economic losses every year: If weeds were allowed to grow with no control measures, about half of corn and soybean crops across the United States and Canada would be lost, costing growers about $43 billion annually, says a team of researchers.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130720.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:07:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130720.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>How does water move through soil?: In the basic water cycle, water falls on the land in some type of precipitation (rain or snow). It either is soaked into the ground or runs off into a body of water &#8211; storm water or natural. Eventually, it returns to the atmosphere. But the story about water movement in soil is complex. Soil scientists call this topic &#8220;soil hydrology.&#8221; Experts now explain how soil texture, soil structure, and gravity influence water movement.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130718.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:07:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130718.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Promise of nearly a year of life on targeted drug not reality for all liver cancer patients, study finds: The median survival for a group of Medicare patients on the drug sorafenib was three months, which was significantly lower than the median survival of nearly 11 months for patients treated with the drug during a phase III clinical trial, report researchers.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130716.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516130716.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Healthy eating gets no boost after corner store interventions, study finds: While many government, community and private interventions look at local corner and convenience stores as prime areas to stoke healthy eating, a new study found that even two years after such an intervention took place, attitudes and purchasing habits didn't change.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125959.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125959.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Improving natural killer cancer therapy: Researchers have discovered a potential way to 'tune up' the immune system's ability to kill cancer cells. In a new paper, they describe their discovery in mice of a tolerance mechanism that restrains the activity of natural killer (NK) cells, and a potential way to overcome it.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125948.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125948.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Theorists smooth the way to modeling quantum friction: Theoretical chemists have pioneered a strategy for modeling quantum friction, or how a particle's environment drags on it, a vexing problem that has frustrated scientists for more than a century.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125946.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125946.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Inaccurate coding of patient data may explain 'weekend effect': Studies that use UK hospital coding data to examine 'weekend effects' for acute conditions, such as stroke, may be undermined by inaccurate coding, suggests new research.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125944.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125944.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Animal training techniques teach robots new tricks: Researchers are using ideas from animal training to help non-expert users teach robots how to do desired tasks.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125939.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125939.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Freight train: Myo1c provides cellular transport for protein crucial to kidney filtration: Researchers used small-angle X-ray scattering to determine the full structure of the motor protein Myo1c and its complex with Neph1, a protein crucial for kidney filtration. Their findings suggest that Myo1c uses the actin cytoskeleton as a 'track' for Neph1 transport -- a finding with translational relevance for glomerular diseases such as diabetic nephropathy, as movement of Neph1 to and from the surface membrane triggers the injury/recovery response.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125935.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:59:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125935.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Self-healing, flexible electronic material restores functions after many breaks: Electronic materials have been a major stumbling block for the advance of flexible electronics because existing materials do not function well after breaking and healing. A new electronic material created by an international team, however, can heal all its functions automatically even after breaking multiple times. This material could improve the durability of wearable electronics.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125349.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:53:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125349.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Scientists genetically engineered world's first Zika virus infectious cDNA clone: A multidisciplinary team is the first in the world to genetically engineer a clone of the Zika virus strain, a development that could expedite many aspects of Zika research, including vaccine and therapeutics development. Cloning the virus unlocks scientists' ability to more quickly develop countermeasures and explore whether or how the Zika virus has evolved to spread more quickly and cause more severe diseases in people.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125347.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:53:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125347.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Hunting for hidden life on worlds orbiting old, red stars: Astronomers have modeled the locations of the habitable zones for aging stars and how long planets can stay in it.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125345.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:53:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125345.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Canada's plans to legalize marijuana contravene UN's international conventions, say experts: The Canadian government's plan to legalize marijuana contravenes its current legal obligations to the United Nation's international drug-control conventions, states a new expert commentary.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125342.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516125342.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>HIV vaccine design should adapt as HIV mutates: Researchers have demonstrated that HIV has evolved to be pre-adapted to the immune response, worsening clinical outcomes in newly infected patients.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115750.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:57:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115750.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>How differences in male, female brains emerge: Nematode worms may not be from Mars or Venus, but they do have sex-specific circuits in their brains that cause the males and females to act differently. According to new research, scientists have determined how these sexually dimorphic (occurring in either males or females) connections arise in the worm nervous system.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115447.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:54:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115447.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Poll: Many parents keep prescription opioids at home: Nearly half of parents whose child had leftover pain medication from a surgery or illness say they kept the prescription opioids at home.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115443.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:54:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115443.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New method of producing random numbers could improve cybersecurity: A new method for producing truly random numbers could be used to encrypt data, make electronic voting more secure, conduct statistically significant polls and more accurately simulate complex systems such as Earth's climate.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115441.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:54:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115441.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Obese or anorexic individuals react differently to taste, study says: Women suffering from anorexia nervosa and those who are obese respond differently to taste, a finding that could lead to new treatments for the eating disorders, report investigators.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115439.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:54:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115439.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>E.coli 'anchors' provide novel way to hijack superbugs: Scientists may have found a way to stop deadly bacteria from infecting patients. The discovery could lead to a whole new way of treating antibiotic-resistant 'superbugs'. The researchers have uncovered what may be an Achilles heel on the bacteria cell membrane that could act as a potential novel drug target.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115437.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:54:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115437.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Polluted dust can impact ocean life thousands of miles away: As climatologists closely monitor the impact of human activity on the world's oceans, researchers have found yet another worrying trend impacting the health of the Pacific Ocean.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115306.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:53:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115306.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Physical activity associated with lower risk for many cancers: Higher levels of leisure-time physical activity were associated with lower risks for 13 types of cancers, according to a new study.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115302.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115302.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New stem cell pathway indicates route to much higher yields in maize, staple crops: Biologists have made an important discovery that helps explain how plants regulate the proliferation of their stem cells. The discovery has near-term implications for increasing the yield of maize and many other staple crops, perhaps by as much as 50 percent.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115300.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115300.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Frequent religious service attendance linked with decreased mortality risk among women: Women who attended religious services more than once per week were more than 30 percent less likely to die during a 16-year-follow-up than women who never attended, according to a new study. Frequent attendees also had significantly lower risk both from cardiovascular- and cancer-related mortality.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115258.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:52:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516115258.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Study reveals how differences in male and female brains emerge: Nematode worms may not be from Mars or Venus, but they do have sex-specific circuits in their brains that cause the males and females to act differently. According to new research published in Nature, scientists have determined how these sexually dimorphic (occurring in either males or females) connections arise in the worm nervous system. The research was funded by the NIH's National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS).</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-reveals-differences-male-female-brains.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:36:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-reveals-differences-male-female-brains.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Neurosurgeon and electrical engineer walk into a lab...: An interdisciplinary team is developing unique technologies to sense and stimulate individual cells of the brain without invasive electrodes.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110607.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:06:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110607.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Tiny organisms have huge effect on world&#8217;s atmosphere: Scientists have discovered how a tiny yet abundant ocean organism helps regulate Earth's climate. They showed that these tiny, hugely abundant bacteria could make the environmentally important gas, dimethyl sulfide.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110502.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:05:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110502.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Implantation of rapid deployment aortic valve found to be durable, safe, and effective: EDWARDS INTUITY valve system shortens duration of interrupted blood flow and heart stoppage during surgery, according to new research.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110500.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110500.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Geologists identify sources of methane, greenhouse gas, in Ohio, Colorado and Texas: Methane comes from various sources, like landfills, bacterial processes in water, cattle and fracking. In testing methane sources at three national sites, geologists found no evidence fracking affected methane concentrations in groundwater in Ohio. At sites in Colorado and Texas, methane sources were founded to be mixed, divided between fracking, cattle and/or landfills.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110425.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:04:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110425.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Farms a major source of air pollution, study finds: Emissions from farms outweigh all other human sources of fine-particulate air pollution in much of the United States, Europe, Russia and China, according to new research. The culprit: fumes from nitrogen-rich fertilizers and animal waste combine in the air with combustion emissions to form solid particles, which constitute a major source of disease and death, according to the new study.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110423.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:04:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110423.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Animal welfare initiatives improves feather cover of cage-free laying hens, new study shows: Recognized welfare outcome assessments within farm assurance schemes have shown a reduction in feather loss and improvement in the welfare of UK cage-free laying hens, according to the findings of a new study.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110419.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:04:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110419.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Robot's in-hand eye maps surroundings, determines hand's location: Before a robot arm can reach into a tight space or pick up a delicate object, the robot needs to know precisely where its hand is. Researchers have shown that a camera attached to the robot's hand can rapidly create a 3-D model of its environment and also locate the hand within that 3-D world.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110416.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 08:04:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516110416.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>New study shows animal welfare initiatives improves feather cover of cage-free laying hens: Recognised welfare outcome assessments within farm assurance schemes have shown a reduction in feather loss and improvement in the welfare of UK cage-free laying hens, according to the findings of a study from the AssureWel project by the University of Bristol, RSPCA and the Soil Association.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-animal-welfare-feather-cage-free-hens.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:59:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-animal-welfare-feather-cage-free-hens.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Stage IIIA non-small cell lung cancer survival rates improved when care includes four specific quality measures: Only 13% of eligible patients studied benefited from all four quality measures and there is a wide disparity of implementation across the patients analyzed, according to a recent presentation.</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516103323.htm</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:33:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2016/05/160516103323.htm</guid></item>
<item><title>Scientist collects 30 sawfly species not previously reported from Arkansas: Sawflies and wood wasps form a group of insects that feed mainly on plants when immature. Field work by Dr. Michael Skvarla, which was conducted during his Ph.D. research at the University of Arkansas, Fayetteville, USA, has uncovered 30 species of these plant-feeding wasps that were previously unknown in the state. The study is published it in the open access journal Biodiversity Data Journal.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-scientist-sawfly-species-previously-arkansas.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-scientist-sawfly-species-previously-arkansas.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Container design important for endangered plant nursery: Recent research at the University of Guam has shown that the use of traditional hard plastic containers in a conservation nursery reduced the quality of the roots of an endangered tree species. The experimental results appeared in the May 2016 issue of the international journal Plant Root. The model plant was Serianthes nelsonii, a species with a known endemic range of only two islands in the Mariana Island archipelago.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-important-endangered-nursery.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 06:35:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-important-endangered-nursery.html</guid></item>
<item><title>How dogs find their way home (without a GPS): Animals' ability to navigate long distances has long been shrouded in mystery. From the skill of racing pigeons to find their way home, to the seasonal breeding migration of the humpback whale, a huge range of creatures are capable of navigating in a consistent, precise and effective way.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-dogs-home-gps.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 06:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-dogs-home-gps.html</guid></item>
<item><title>A 'sixth sense' for humidity helps insects stay out of climatic trouble: The amount of water vapor in the air &#8211; humidity &#8211; profoundly alters our experience of the environment around us. A hot, dry morning in the desert of California feels miles apart from a hot, sticky one in the Cambodian jungle.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-sixth-humidity-insects-climatic.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 04:33:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-sixth-humidity-insects-climatic.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Prawn spawn secrets unlocked in 3D images: Discovering the secrets of how one of the world's most popular prawn species produces sperm and transfers it to create the next generation could help free aquaculture from reliance on brood stock from the wild.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-prawn-spawn-secrets-3d-images.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 03:34:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-prawn-spawn-secrets-3d-images.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Maize genome 'dark matter' discovery a boon for breeders: (<i>Cornell University</i>) In a landmark finding, Cornell University and Florida State University researchers report they have identified 1 to 2 percent of the maize genome that turns genes on and off, so they may now focus their attention on these areas for more efficient plant breeding.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cu-mg051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cu-mg051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Fort McMurray fire continues in Alberta: (<i>NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center</i>) On May 12, 2016, a total of 17 wildfires were still burning in the vicinity of Fort McMurray, Canada. Provincial authorities still considered one of those fires to be 'out of control.' As of May 12, fires in that part of Alberta had burned up at least 2,410 square kilometers (930 square miles) of land.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nsfc-fmf051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nsfc-fmf051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>FSU-Cornell team defines meaningful part of maize genome: (<i>Florida State University</i>) Using a genetic mapping technique developed at Florida State University, FSU and Cornell University researchers have shown that a small percentage of the entire maize genome is responsible for almost half of a plant's trait diversity.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/fsu-ftd051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/fsu-ftd051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Biodiversity protects fish from climate change: (<i>Smithsonian</i>) Fish provide protein to billions of people and are an especially critical food source in the developing world. Today marine biologists confirmed a key factor that could help them thrive through the coming decades: biodiversity. Communities with more fish species are more productive and more resilient to rising temperatures and temperature swings, according to a new study from the Smithsonian's Tennenbaum Marine Observatories Network and other international institutions.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/s-bpf051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/s-bpf051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Agriculture Secretary Vilsack announces $130 million available for foundational agricultural research, education and extension: (<i>National Institute of Food and Agriculture </i>) The US Department of Agriculture today announced that $130 million in funding is available for research, education, and extension projects to support sustainable, productive and economically viable plant and animal production systems, including certified organic production.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/niof-asv051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/niof-asv051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Methionine could be key to improving pregnancy rate in dairy cattle: (<i>University of Illinois College of Agricultural, Consumer and Environmental Sciences</i>) Research at the University of Illinois has shown that adding methionine to the diets of Holstein cows during the prepartum and postpartum periods may impact the preimplantation embryo in a way that enhances its capacity for survival.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoic-mcb051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoic-mcb051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Cooling cows efficiently with water spray: (<i>Elsevier Health Sciences</i>) Dairies use intermittent sprinkler systems to cool cows in warm weather, but little experimental work has been done to determine how much water is needed to achieve beneficial effects. A group of dairy scientists conducted a study at the University of California, Davis, to examine the effects of using low-flow sprinkler systems that cut water use for this purpose by nearly 75 percent. Their research is published in the current issue of the Journal of Dairy Science&#174;.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ehs-cce051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ehs-cce051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Farms have become a major air-pollution source: (<i>The Earth Institute at Columbia University</i>) A new study says that emissions from farms outweigh all other human sources of fine-particulate air pollution in much of the United States, Europe, Russia and China. The culprit: fumes from nitrogen-rich fertilizers and animal waste that combine in the air with industrial emissions to form solid particles -- a huge source of disease and death. The good news: if industrial emissions decline in coming decades, as most projections say, fine-particle pollution will go down even if fertilizer use doubles as expected.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/teia-ams051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/teia-ams051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>World's richest source of oceanographic data now operational at Rutgers: (<i>Rutgers University</i>) The data center for the pioneering Ocean Observatories Initiative, which collects and shares data from more than 800 sophisticated instruments and a transmission network across the Atlantic and Pacific oceans, is now operating at Rutgers University.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ru-wrs051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ru-wrs051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Watching whisky dry for science (video): (<i>American Chemical Society</i>) Have you ever watched paint dry? How about whisky? It turns out whisky could hold some chemical clues to making better paints. Princeton researcher Howard Stone and photographer Ernie Button wanted to figure out whisky's unique drying properties. The Speaking of Chemistry team then compared dried whisky rings to another popular beverage, coffee. Sophia Cai serves the science, straight, in our latest video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XfXB-EAMOZw.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/acs-wwd051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/acs-wwd051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Farms have become a major air-pollution source: (<i>American Geophysical Union</i>) Emissions from farms outweigh all other human sources of fine-particulate air pollution in much of the United States, Europe, Russia and China, according to new research. The culprit: fumes from nitrogen-rich fertilizers and animal waste combine in the air with combustion emissions to form solid particles, which constitute a major source of disease and death, according to the new study.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/agu-fam051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/agu-fam051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Poor countries to bear brunt of climate change despite emitting least CO2: (<i>University of East Anglia</i>) Many of the world's poorest countries are expected to experience daily heat extremes due to climate change sooner than wealthier nations.New findings published today in Environmental Research Letters show that the poorest fifth of the global population will be the first to experience more frequent heat extremes -- despite cumulatively emitting the least amounts of CO2.Countries including those in the Horn of Africa and West Africa are likely to be worst affected.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoea-pct051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoea-pct051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Russian researchers developed an ecological method for cleaning lakes from oil: (<i>National Research Tomsk State University</i>) The technology, developed by TSU, best suited for lakes with thick sediments: stony, clay or sandy bottom. This method allows cleaning both sediments and water and there are no any restrictions on the depth of the pond.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nrts-rrd051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nrts-rrd051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>What foods can help fight the risk of chronic inflammation?: (<i>University of Liverpool</i>) A new study by the University of Liverpool's Institute of Ageing and Chronic Disease has identified food stuffs that can help prevent chronic inflammation that contributes to many leading causes of death.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uol-wfc051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uol-wfc051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Polluted dust can impact ocean life thousands of miles away, study says: (<i>Georgia Institute of Technology</i>) As climatologists closely monitor the impact of human activity on the world's oceans, researchers at the Georgia Institute of Technology have found yet another worrying trend impacting the health of the Pacific Ocean.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/giot-pdc051316.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/giot-pdc051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>New stem cell pathway indicates route to much higher yields in maize, staple crops: (<i>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory</i>) Biologists at Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory (CSHL) have made an important discovery that helps explain how plants regulate the proliferation of their stem cells.  The discovery has near-term implications for increasing the yield of maize and many other staple crops, perhaps by as much as 50 percent.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cshl-nsc051216.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cshl-nsc051216.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Tiny ocean organism has big role in climate regulation: (<i>University of Exeter</i>) Scientists have discovered that a tiny, yet plentiful, ocean organism is playing an important role in the regulation of the Earth's climate.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoe-too051216.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoe-too051216.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Iron fertilization won't work in much of Pacific, says study: (<i>The Earth Institute at Columbia University</i>) Over the past half-million years, the equatorial Pacific Ocean has seen five spikes in the amount of iron-laden dust blown in from the continents. In theory, those bursts should have turbo-charged the growth of the ocean's carbon-capturing algae -- algae need iron to grow -- but a new study shows that the excess iron had little to no effect.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/teia-ifw051216.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/teia-ifw051216.php</guid></item>
<item><title>A shaggy dog story: The contagious cancer that conquered the world: (<i>University of Cambridge</i>) A contagious form of cancer that can spread between dogs during mating has highlighted the extent to which dogs accompanied human travelers throughout our seafaring history. But the tumors also provide surprising insights into how cancers evolve by 'stealing' DNA from their host.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc-asd051216.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc-asd051216.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Exercise, more than diet, key to preventing obesity: (<i>University of Missouri-Columbia</i>) Two factors -- metabolism and gut microbes -- have been credited by researchers as key players in the fight against obesity. However, there is an ongoing debate about whether exercise or diet better promotes metabolism and healthy shifts in gut microbes, the microscopic organisms in our intestines that break down food and can contribute to decreased obesity. New research from the University of Missouri confirms exercise plays a significant role in the fight against obesity.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uom-emt051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uom-emt051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Breast cancer tumor-initiating cells use mTOR signaling to recruit suppressor cells to promote tumor: (<i>Baylor College of Medicine</i>) Baylor College of Medicine researchers report a new mechanism that helps cancer cells engage myeloid-derived suppressor cells.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/bcom-bct051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/bcom-bct051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Immunization with bacteria promotes stress resilience, coping behaviors in mice: (<i>University of California - San Diego</i>) Injections of the soil bacterium Mycobacterium vaccae promote stress resilience and improve coping behaviors in mice, according to a new study led by researchers at University of California San Diego School of Medicine and University of Colorado Boulder. The researchers also found that M. vaccae prevented stress-induced colitis, a typical symptom of inflammatory bowel disease, suggesting that immunization with the bacteria may have wide-ranging health benefits.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc--iwb051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc--iwb051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>New packaging advances prolongs veggie freshness: (<i>Michigan State University</i>) New advances in packaging at Michigan State University can help produce stay fresh longer. Eva Almenar, with MSU's School of Packaging, focused on onions, one of the highest-volume vegetables sold worldwide. Her team's results, featured in a recent issue of International Journal of Food Microbiology, show that improvements can enhance the safety and improve the quality of the ubiquitous vegetable.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/msu-npa051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/msu-npa051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Slips of the lip stay all in the family: (<i>Duke University</i>) It's happened to many of us: While looking at someone you know very well, you blurt out the wrong name. The name you blurt is not just any old name, though, says new research from Duke University that finds 'misnaming' follows predictable patterns.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/du-sot051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/du-sot051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Technique improves the efficacy of fuel cells: (<i>Harvard John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences</i>) Solid oxide fuel cells, which rely on low- cost ceramic materials, are among the most efficient and promising type of fuel cell. Now, researchers from the Harvard John A. Paulson School of Engineering and Applied Sciences have found a way to harness the quantum behavior of these fuel cells to make them even more efficient and robust. In doing so, they've observed a new type of phase transition in an oxide material.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/hjap-tit051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/hjap-tit051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>JFK Partners joins launch of Spark, nation's largest autism research study: (<i>Children's Hospital Colorado</i>) JFK Partners at the CU Anschutz Medical Campus in Aurora, CO recently helped launch SPARK, an online research initiative designed to become the largest autism study ever undertaken in the United States. Sponsored by the Simons Foundation Autism Research Initiative, SPARK will collect information and DNA for genetic analysis from 50,000 individuals with autism -- and their families -- to advance our understanding of the causes of this condition and to hasten the discovery of supports and treatments.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/chc-jpj051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/chc-jpj051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Converting cells to burn fat, not store it: (<i>McGill University</i>) Researchers have uncovered a new molecular pathway for stimulating the body to burn fat -- a discovery that could help fight obesity, diabetes and cardiovascular disease.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/mu-cct051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/mu-cct051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Teamwork enables bacterial survival: (<i>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</i>) MIT researchers have found that two strains of E. coli bacteria, each resistant to one antibiotic, can protect each other in an environment where both drugs are present.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/miot-teb051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/miot-teb051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>ASHG opposes revised EEOC regulations weakening genetic privacy: (<i>American Society of Human Genetics</i>) The American Society of Human Genetics opposes the US Equal Employment Opportunity Commission's (EEOC) newly revised Regulations under the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) and under the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act (GINA). 'These revisions will significantly weaken the patient privacy protections in the ADA and GINA,' said Derek T. Scholes, Ph.D., ASHG Director of Science Policy.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/asoh-aor051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/asoh-aor051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Features of the 2016 Asia Pacific Lung Cancer Conference (APLCC): (<i>International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer</i>) The 2016 IASLC Asia Pacific Lung Cancer Conference, held May 13-15, was organized under the aegis of International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer, Thai Society of Clinical Oncology, Chiang Mai Lung Cancer Group, Faculty of Medicine at the Chiang Mai University (CMU and the local organizing committee of APLCC 2016.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/iaft-fot051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/iaft-fot051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Healthy eating gets no boost after corner store interventions, Drexel study finds: (<i>Drexel University</i>) While many government, community and private interventions look at local corner and convenience stores as prime areas to stoke healthy eating, a Drexel study found that even two years after such an intervention took place, attitudes and purchasing habits didn't change.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/du-heg051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/du-heg051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>HIV vaccine design should adapt as HIV virus mutates: (<i>University of Alabama at Birmingham</i>) Researchers from UAB, Emory and Microsoft demonstrate that HIV has evolved to be pre-adapted to the immune response, worsening clinical outcomes in newly infected patients.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoaa-hvd051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoaa-hvd051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Freight train: Myo1c provides cellular transport for protein crucial to kidney filtration: (<i>Medical University of South Carolina</i>) Researchers at the Medical University of South Carolina used small-angle X-ray scattering to determine the full structure of the motor protein Myo1c and its complex with Neph1, a protein crucial for kidney filtration. Their findings suggest that Myo1c uses the actin cytoskeleton as a 'track' for Neph1 transport -- a finding with translational relevance for glomerular diseases such as diabetic nephropathy, as movement of Neph1 to and from the surface membrane triggers the injury/recovery response.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/muos-ftm051316.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/muos-ftm051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Why is female sexuality more flexible than male sexuality?: (<i>Wiley</i>) A new evolutionary theory argues that women may have been evolutionarily designed to be sexually fluid -- changing their sexual desires and identities from lesbian, to bisexual, to heterosexual and back again -- in order to allow them to have sex with their co-wives in polygamous marriages, therefore reducing conflict and tension inherent in such marriages while at the same time successfully reproducing with their husbands in heterosexual unions.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/w-wif051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/w-wif051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Overpasses and underpasses for migrating animals may reduce collisions with automobiles: (<i>Wiley</i>) In the western United States, mule deer and pronghorn (animals that are similar to antelopes) undergo annual migrations that place them and drivers at risk for collisions when the animals cross busy roadways. A new study evaluated overpasses and underpasses as alternative routes for the animals during migration.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/w-oau051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/w-oau051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>NIH-funded study reveals how differences in male and female brains emerge: (<i>NIH/National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke</i>) Nematode worms may not be from Mars or Venus, but they do have sex-specific circuits in their brains that cause the males and females to act differently. According to new research published in Nature, scientists have determined how these sexually dimorphic (occurring in either males or females) connections arise in the worm nervous system. The research was funded by the NIH's National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS).</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nion-nsr051616.php</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/nion-nsr051616.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Container design important for endangered plant nursery: (<i>University of Guam</i>) Changing a common nursery procedure could increase the survival rate of endangered tree.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uog-cdi051516.php</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uog-cdi051516.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Hatchlings give hope for endangered songbird's survival: The first captive-bred Florida Grasshopper Sparrow hatched this week under the care of researchers with Florida International University's Tropical Conservation Institute.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-hatchlings-endangered-songbird-survival.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 11:50:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-hatchlings-endangered-songbird-survival.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Sugar-free gum can be deadly for dogs: (HealthDay)&#8212;Here's an alert for all dog lovers: Sugarless chewing gum isn't good for your pooch. In fact, it could be deadly.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-sugar-free-gum-deadly-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 11:28:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-sugar-free-gum-deadly-dogs.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Proton-conducting material found in electrosensory organs of sharks: Sharks, skates, and rays can detect very weak electric fields produced by prey and other animals using an array of unusual organs known as the ampullae of Lorenzini. Exactly how these electrosensory organs work has remained a mystery, but a new study has revealed an important clue that may have implications for other fields of research.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-proton-conducting-material-electrosensory-sharks.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-proton-conducting-material-electrosensory-sharks.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Coral stress test found in the genes: Unique sections of coral DNA can indicate a higher tolerance to environmental stress, researchers have revealed for the first time.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-coral-stress-genes.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 11:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-coral-stress-genes.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Loud and low-carb: Cicadas are back in Ohio, West Virginia: The 17-year cicadas are coming again, millions of them, with their unnerving red eyes, orange wings and cacophonous mating song that can drown out the noise of passing jet planes.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-loud-low-carb-cicadas-ohio-west.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 06:27:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-loud-low-carb-cicadas-ohio-west.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Cooperative fish take turns with gender roles: Chalk bass (Serranus tortugarum) are small sea bass in the grouper family. What makes these fish interesting is that they are simultaneous hermaphrodites: they have both male and female reproductive tissue at the same time.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-cooperative-fish-gender-roles.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 06:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-cooperative-fish-gender-roles.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Possums in NZ prefer leaves high in available protein: Researchers at The Australian National University (ANU) have found possums in New Zealand prefer to eat leaves high in available protein, giving authorities new evidence to help them limit possum damage to New Zealand's forests.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-possums-nz-high-protein.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 06:16:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-possums-nz-high-protein.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Male birds may sing, but females are faster at discriminating sounds: It may well be that only male zebra finches can sing, but the females are faster at learning to discriminate sounds. Leiden researchers publish their findings in the scientific journal Animal Behaviour.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-male-birds-females-faster-discriminating.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:35:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-male-birds-females-faster-discriminating.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Five ways to protect your pet from Lyme disease: Lyme disease is transmitted to people, dogs and cats when a deer tick infected with the bacterium Borrelia burgdorferi attaches itself to the skin for a blood feast.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-ways-pet-lyme-disease.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 05:33:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-ways-pet-lyme-disease.html</guid></item>
<item><title>ASU, White House to investigate mysteries of the microbiome: (<i>Arizona State University</i>) The White House Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) announced today a new National Microbiome Initiative (NMI) to foster the integrated study of microbiomes across different ecosystems.Helping lead the initiative is Dr. Ferran Garcia-Pichel, dean of natural sciences in the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences at Arizona State University and founding director of the Biodesign Center for Fundamental and Applied Microbiomics.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/asu-awh051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/asu-awh051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Carbon capture is substantial in secondary tropical forests: (<i>Clemson University</i>) One of the most effective methods for capturing carbon from the atmosphere in the tropics of Latin America -- allowing secondary forests to regenerate on their own -- is overlooked by global climate change policies. Scientists explain how these forests quickly become substantial, important players in the fight to slow climate change.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cu-cci051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/cu-cci051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Natural regeneration of tropical forests reaps benefits: (<i>University of Connecticut</i>) Research shows that natural forest regrowth in Latin America  plays major role in climate mitigation and carbon sequestration.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc-nro051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uoc-nro051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Wildfires: More people, less fires: (<i>Karlsruher Institut f&#252;r Technologie (KIT) </i>) Every year, about 350 million hectares of land are devastated by fires worldwide, this corresponds to about the size of India. Previous studies often considered climate change to be the most important factor. Now, a group of scientists, including researchers of Karlsruhe Institute of Technology, has found that population development has the same impact at least. The results are presented in the Nature Climate Change journal.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/kift-wmp051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/kift-wmp051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Louisiana Tech University students present research at Senior Projects Conference: (<i>Louisiana Tech University</i>) Senior class students from Louisiana Tech University's College of Engineering and Science showcased their research and innovative solutions to real-world problems at the College of Engineering and Science Senior Projects Conference held recently on the Louisiana Tech campus.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ltu-ltu051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/ltu-ltu051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Genetic history of the 'ship of the desert' revealed: (<i>University of Nottingham</i>) A unique and pioneering study of the ancient and modern DNA of the 'ship of the desert' -- the single humped camel or dromedary -- has shed new light on how its use by human societies has shaped its genetic diversity.</title><link>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uon-gho051316.php</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.eurekalert.org/pub_releases/2016-05/uon-gho051316.php</guid></item>
<item><title>Rare human disease found in dogs: A rare, severe form of pulmonary hypertension, which up until now, has only been classified as a human lung disease, has also been discovered in dogs according to a Michigan State University study.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-rare-human-disease-dogs.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 12:05:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-rare-human-disease-dogs.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Mice cooperate if they benefit: Four people meet for dinner in a restaurant and split the check four ways. Anyone who ordered more or something more expensive than the others gains an advantage from the situation. Social dilemmas like this one also occur in animals - such as during communal offspring care. Biologists from the University of Zurich studied how house mice are able to prevent social dilemmas and still cooperate. The results of their study reveal that house mice adjust their willingness to cooperate to the to the expected pay-off.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-mice-cooperate-benefit.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 10:47:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-mice-cooperate-benefit.html</guid></item>
<item><title>When dung beetles dance, they photograph the firmament: The discovery that dung beetles use the light of the Milky Way to navigate in the world has received much praise. Researchers at Lund University in Sweden have now taken a new step in understanding the existence of these unique beetles: when the beetles dance on top of a ball of dung, they simultaneously take a photograph - a snapshot - of how celestial bodies are positioned.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-dung-beetles-firmament.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 09:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-dung-beetles-firmament.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Homosexual activity documented in female gorillas for the first time: As part of a study facilitated through the Dian Fossey Gorilla Fund International, a researcher from The University of Western Australia has documented the first detailed evidence of homosexual behaviour in female gorillas.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-homosexual-documented-female-gorillas.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 04:48:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-homosexual-documented-female-gorillas.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Chimpanzee enclosure redesign translates wild chimpanzee research to zoo settings: University of Birmingham scientists have developed a new way to redesign chimpanzee enclosures to translate research on wild chimpanzees into zoos to help preserve the behavioural and physiological adaptations that make the species unique.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-chimpanzee-enclosure-redesign-wild-zoo.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 04:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-chimpanzee-enclosure-redesign-wild-zoo.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Rare Sumatran rhino calf born in Indonesia: A Sumatran rhino gave birth at a sanctuary in Indonesia on Thursday, an official said, taking the critically endangered species a step further away from extinction.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-rare-sumatran-rhino-calf-born.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 04:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-rare-sumatran-rhino-calf-born.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Colour constancy in chickens: Chickens can find the correct colour in redder lighting conditions, researchers from Lund University and the University of Bristol have found. Their study indicates that &#8211; like us &#8211; chickens have colour constancy (a feature of the colour perception system which ensures that the perceived colour of objects remains relatively constant under varying illumination conditions).</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-colour-constancy-chickens.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:35:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-colour-constancy-chickens.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Highway noise deters communication between birds: New research from University of Florida Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences researchers shows birds may be avoiding habitats near noisy highways because they can't hear fellow birds' alarms that warn them of attacking hawks or owls.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-highway-noise-deters-birds.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 03:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-highway-noise-deters-birds.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Effects of Chlorpyrifos and Lambda- and Gamma-Cyhalothrin on Suppression of Aster Leafhoppers, Macrosteles quadrilineatus (Hemiptera: Cicadellidae) in Spring Wheat: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/32/1">Volume 32, Issue 1</a>, Page 25-34, January 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-15.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 21:13:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-15.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Study finds some birds process sound much as people do, suggesting stream segregation is not a uniquely human ability: While analyzing and untangling multiple environmental sounds is an important social tool for humans, for animals that analysis is a critical survival skill. Yet humans and animals use similar cues to make sense of their acoustic worlds, according to new research from the University at Buffalo.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-birds-people-stream-segregation-uniquely.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 13:37:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-birds-people-stream-segregation-uniquely.html</guid></item>
<item><title>You are what you eat: Biologists map genetic pathways of nutrition-based species traits: Biologists at Indiana University have significantly advanced understanding of the genetic pathways that control the appearance of different physical traits in the same species depending on nutritional conditions experienced during development.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-biologists-genetic-pathways-nutrition-based-species.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 13:29:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-biologists-genetic-pathways-nutrition-based-species.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Wolf pups more likely to play on equal terms with similarly aged partners: Wolf puppy play behaviors may be influenced by their play partner's age, according to a study published May 11, 2016 in the open-access journal PLOS ONE by Jennifer Essler from the Messerli Research Institute (Vetmed Vienna) and the Wolf Science Center, Austria, and colleagues.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-wolf-pups-equal-terms-similarly.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 11:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-wolf-pups-equal-terms-similarly.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Mysterious mounds created by earthworms: Mysterious spectacular mounds found in the earth in tropical wetlands in South America are created by earthworms, researchers have found.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-mysterious-mounds-earthworms.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-mysterious-mounds-earthworms.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Study reveals fox squirrels' tell-tail signs of frustration: Fox squirrels flick their tails when they can't get a cherished nut in much the same way that humans kick a vending machine that fails to deliver the anticipated soda or candy bar, according to new research from the University of California, Berkeley.</title><link>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-reveals-fox-squirrels-tell-tail-frustration.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 10:12:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://phys.org/news/2016-05-reveals-fox-squirrels-tell-tail-frustration.html</guid></item>
<item><title>Seasonal phoresy as an overwintering strategy of a phytophagous mite: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160506/srep25483/full/srep25483.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160506/srep25483/full/srep25483.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>New long-proboscid lacewings of the mid-Cretaceous provide insights into ancient plant-pollinator interactions: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160505/srep25382/full/srep25382.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160505/srep25382/full/srep25382.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Specific Cues Associated With Honey Bee Social Defence against Varroa destructor Infested Brood: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160503/srep25444/full/srep25444.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160503/srep25444/full/srep25444.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Gut microbial communities of social bees: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/nrmicro/journal/v14/n6/full/nrmicro.2016.43.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/nrmicro/journal/v14/n6/full/nrmicro.2016.43.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Spider behaviors include oral sexual encounters: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160429/srep25128/full/srep25128.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160429/srep25128/full/srep25128.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Traumatic insemination and female counter-adaptation in Strepsiptera (Insecta): </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160429/srep25052/full/srep25052.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160429/srep25052/full/srep25052.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Density-Dependent Responses of Natural Enemies to Soybean Aphid (Hemiptera: Aphididae) Populations: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 168-177, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-30.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-30.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Increasing Trophic Complexity Influences Aphid Attendance by Ants (Hymenoptera: Formicidae) and Predation: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 151-164, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-32.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-32.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Sucrose Mixed with Spinosad Enhances Kill and Reduces Oviposition of Rhagoletis indifferens (Diptera: Tephritidae) Under Low Food Availability: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 101-112, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-33.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-33.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Laboratory Assays of the Effects of Oxfendazole on Biological Parameters of Galleria mellonella (Lepidoptera: Pyralidae): Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 129-137, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-36.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-36.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Geographical Distribution of Bagrada hilaris (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) in Mexico: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 165-167, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-41.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-41.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Ectoparasites of White-Tailed Deer (Artiodactyla: Cervidae) in Southeastern Georgia, USA: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 113-121, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-27.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-27.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Disruption of Coptotermes formosanus (Isoptera: Rhinotermitidae) Gut Microbiota Reproduction and its Consequences for the Cellulolytic System: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 138-150, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-28.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-28.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Cannibalistic Oophagy in Halyomorpha halys (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) Laboratory Colonies: Journal of Entomological Science, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/ents/51/2">Volume 51, Issue 2</a>, Page 122-128, April 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-29.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 23:47:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.18474/JES15-29.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>The utility of DNA metabarcoding for studying the response of arthropod diversity and composition to land-use change in the tropics: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160426/srep24965/full/srep24965.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160426/srep24965/full/srep24965.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Analysis of proteome dynamics inside the silk gland lumen of Bombyx mori: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160422/srep21158/full/srep21158.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160422/srep21158/full/srep21158.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Infection pattern and transmission potential of chikungunya virus in two New World laboratory-adapted Aedes aegypti strains: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160422/srep24729/full/srep24729.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160422/srep24729/full/srep24729.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>The effects of Bt Cry1Ie toxin on bacterial diversity in the midgut of Apis mellifera ligustica (Hymenoptera: Apidae): </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160419/srep24664/full/srep24664.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160419/srep24664/full/srep24664.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>New Records of Mayflies (Ephemeroptera) from Kenora District and Northwestern Ontario, Canada: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 341-350, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0505?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0505?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Preliminary Survey of the Scarabaeoidea (Coleoptera) of Valles Caldera National Preserve (New Mexico, USA): Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 333-340, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0504?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0504?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Range Extension for Orthocladius (Mesorthocladius) lamellatus (S&#198;Ther, 2005) (Diptera: Chironomidae) in North America Based on Records from Headwater Streams in Missouri, USA: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 327-332, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0503?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0503?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Attraction of Insects to Incandescent, Compact Fluorescent, Halogen, and Led Lamps in a Light Trap: Implications for Light Pollution and Urban Ecologies: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 315-326, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0502?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0502?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>The Sweat Bee Lasioglossum occidens is a Potential Pollinator of Calanthe aristulifera in the Oceanic Izu Islands: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 368-373, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0509?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0509?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Comparison of Foraging Activity between Mason Bee Osmia orientalis (Hymenoptera: Megachilidae) and Honybees for Wild Raspberry Rubus hirsutus (Rosales: Rosaceae): Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 363-367, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0508?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0508?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Colony Structure in Tapinoma sessile Ants of Northcentral Colorado: A Research Note: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 357-362, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0507?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0507?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>New Species of Exix Mason, 1981 (Hymenoptera: Braconidae, Microgastrinae) from Brazil: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 351-356, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0506?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0506?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>New Editorial E-Mail Address: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 378-378, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0512?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0512?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Erratum in Entomological news 125(4): Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 377-377, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0511?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0511?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Myiasis of Sylvilagus floridanus by a Bot Fly Cuterebra Species (Diptera: Oestridae) in a Xeric Shrub Land of Central Mexico: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 374-376, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0510?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0510?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>National Moth Week: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 379-379, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0514?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0514?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Field Trip Opportunities: Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 379-379, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0513?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0513?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>New Species of the Hercostomus nanlingensis Group from Tibet (Diptera: Dolichopodidae): Entomological News, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/entn/125/5">Volume 125, Issue 5</a>, Page 305-314, March 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0501?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:50:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3157/021.125.0501?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Characterization of the natural enemy community attacking cotton aphid in the Bt cotton ecosystem in Northern China: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160414/srep24273/full/srep24273.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160414/srep24273/full/srep24273.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>The Commercial Bumble Bee Industry May Have Helped Spread Nosema to Wild Bee Populations: When most people think about bee pollinators in U.S. agriculture, they probably think of honey bees. However, bumble bees can also be used, especially in green houses where crops like tomatoes or peppers are grown. In fact, several companies sell bumble bee hives through the mail. In the late 1990s, populations of the western bumble [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=5449&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/04/04/the-commercial-bumble-bee-industry-may-have-helped-spread-nosema-to-wild-bee-populations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/04/04/the-commercial-bumble-bee-industry-may-have-helped-spread-nosema-to-wild-bee-populations/</guid></item>
<item><title>Insight into the feeding behavior of predatory mites on Beauveria bassiana, an arthropod pathogen: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160404/srep24062/full/srep24062.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160404/srep24062/full/srep24062.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Expansion of a bitter taste receptor family in a polyphagous insect herbivore: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160401/srep23666/full/srep23666.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160401/srep23666/full/srep23666.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Ingestion of Bt corn pollen containing Cry1Ab/2Aj or Cry1Ac does not harm Propylea japonica larvae: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160323/srep23507/full/srep23507.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160323/srep23507/full/srep23507.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Putting scales into evolutionary time: the divergence of major scale insect lineages (Hemiptera) predates the radiation of modern angiosperm hosts: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160322/srep23487/full/srep23487.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160322/srep23487/full/srep23487.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Genome-wide identification and developmental expression profiling of long noncoding RNAs during Drosophila metamorphosis: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160321/srep23330/full/srep23330.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160321/srep23330/full/srep23330.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>High phylogenetic diversity is preserved in species-poor high-elevation temperate moth assemblages: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160316/srep23045/full/srep23045.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160316/srep23045/full/srep23045.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Comparison of fitness traits and their plasticity on multiple plants for Sitobion avenae infected and cured of a secondary endosymbiont: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160316/srep23177/full/srep23177.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160316/srep23177/full/srep23177.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Compound eye and ocellar structure for walking and flying modes of locomotion in the Australian ant, Camponotus consobrinus: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160315/srep22331/full/srep22331.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160315/srep22331/full/srep22331.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>New fossil insect order Permopsocida elucidates major radiation and evolution of suction feeding in hemimetabolous insects (Hexapoda: Acercaria): </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160310/srep23004/full/srep23004.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160310/srep23004/full/srep23004.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Lepidopteran defence droplets - a composite physical and chemical weapon against potential predators: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160304/srep22407/full/srep22407.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160304/srep22407/full/srep22407.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>A global bionomic database for the dominant vectors of human malaria: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/articles/sdata201614?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/articles/sdata201614?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Starving honey bee (Apis mellifera) larvae signal pheromonally to worker bees: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160229/srep22359/full/srep22359.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160229/srep22359/full/srep22359.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Evolution of the assassin&#8217;s arms: insights from a phylogeny of combined transcriptomic and ribosomal DNA data (Heteroptera: Reduvioidea): </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160226/srep22177/full/srep22177.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160226/srep22177/full/srep22177.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Field trials to evaluate the effects of transgenic cry1Ie maize on the community characteristics of arthropod natural enemies: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160226/srep22102/full/srep22102.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160226/srep22102/full/srep22102.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Parasite infection accelerates age polyethism in young honey bees: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160225/srep22042/full/srep22042.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160225/srep22042/full/srep22042.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>The role of photo-electric properties of silk cocoon membrane in pupal metamorphosis: A natural solar cell: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160224/srep21915/full/srep21915.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160224/srep21915/full/srep21915.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>The green peach aphid Myzus persicae perform better on pre-infested Chinese cabbage Brassica pekinensis by enhancing host plant nutritional quality: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160224/srep21954/full/srep21954.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160224/srep21954/full/srep21954.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Radio Tagging Bumble Bees to Figure Out What the Buzz Is All About: By Jeremy Hemberger Bees are on a lot of folk&#8217;s minds these days, and for good reason. They provide pollination services to over 70% of the crops worldwide, helping to get us the delicious and nutritious foods that we love, like apples, cucumbers, cherries, berries, and more. Despite their importance across the planet, they&#8217;ve taken [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=5209&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/02/23/radio-tagging-bumble-bees-to-figure-out-what-the-buzz-is-all-about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 03:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/02/23/radio-tagging-bumble-bees-to-figure-out-what-the-buzz-is-all-about/</guid></item>
<item><title>Comparative Infectivity of Homologous and Heterologous Nucleopolyhedroviruses against Beet Armyworm Larvae: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/32/1">Volume 32, Issue 1</a>, Page 13-24, January 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-04.2?af=R</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 01:16:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-04.2?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Plant essential oils and potassium metabisulfite as repellents for Drosophila suzukii (Diptera: Drosophilidae): </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160219/srep21432/full/srep21432.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160219/srep21432/full/srep21432.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>Laser induced mortality of Anopheles stephensi mosquitoes: </title><link>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160218/srep20936/full/srep20936.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.nature.com/srep/2016/160218/srep20936/full/srep20936.html?WT.feed_name=subjects_entomology</guid></item>
<item><title>An Opportunity to Study Bees and Pollination in Costa Rica: By Gerrit van de Klashorst The importance of bees and other pollinators for natural and agricultural ecosystems has been well documented. But during the past decades, pollinators have been in decline in North America and Europe. This decline is attributed to a number of factors, including pesticides, habitat loss caused by changing land use, and [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=5168&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/02/15/an-opportunity-to-study-bees-and-pollination-in-costa-rica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 03:33:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2016/02/15/an-opportunity-to-study-bees-and-pollination-in-costa-rica/</guid></item>
<item><title>Vertical Y-tube Assay for Evaluation of Arthropod Response to Plant Materials: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/32/1">Volume 32, Issue 1</a>, Page 7-12, January 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-32.1.7?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 21:28:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-32.1.7?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>A survey of Drosophila species on Santa Catalina Island with an emphasis on the repleta species group (Diptera: Drosophilidae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 1-9, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-020.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-020.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Reviewer Acknowledgement: Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 38-38, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/1947-5144-121.1-4.38?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/1947-5144-121.1-4.38?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>One new species of the subgenus Eriocera Macquart from China (Diptera: Limoniidae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 10-12, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-022.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-022.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>The Seasonal and Nocturnal Attraction of Proarna and Pacarina Cicadas to Lights in the Caribbean Floodplain of Costa Rica and in French Guiana (Hemiptera: Cicadidae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 13-17, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-RA-027.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-RA-027.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Three new species of the genus Telostholus Haupt from China, with a key to the species of the genus (Hymenoptera: Pompilidae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 27-34, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-017.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-RA-017.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Taxonomic notes on Vespinae (Hymenoptera: Vespidae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 35-37, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-RA-024.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-RA-024.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Redescription of the plant bug Miris persicus Reuter (Hemiptera: Heteroptera: Miridae: Mirinae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 18-22, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-SN-019.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/14-SN-019.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>First report Thaumastocoris peregrinus in Eucalyptus plantations in the State of Sergipe, Brazil (Hemiptera: Thaumastocoridae): Entomologica Americana, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/nynt.1/121/1-4">Volume 121, Issue 1-4</a>, Page 23-26, 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-SN-025.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 20:13:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.1664/15-SN-025.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Lethal High Temperature Extremes of the Brown Marmorated Stink Bug (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) and Efficacy of Commercial Heat Treatments for Control in Export Shipping Cargo: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/32/1">Volume 32, Issue 1</a>, Page 1-6, January 2016. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-32.1.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 00:42:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-32.1.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Autosomal Short Tandem Repeats and an Alu Insertion Polymorphism Are Detectable in Cimex lectularius L. (Hemiptera: Cimicidae) for 48 Hours after Human Blood Ingestion: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 62-69, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-03.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 02:28:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-03.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Toxicities of Neonicotinoid Insecticides for Systemic Control of Brown Marmorated Stink Bug (Hemiptera: Pentatomidae) in Fruiting Vegetables: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 70-80, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-06.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 02:27:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-06.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Kudzu-deprived First-generation Megacopta cribraria (F.) (Heteroptera: Plataspidae) Are Capable of Developing on Alternative Legume Species: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 52-61, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-08.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 01:11:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE15-08.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Parasitization of the Potato Aphid, Macrosiphum euphorbiae (Thomas), by Aphelinus asychis Walker in Greenhouses in India: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 47-51, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-27.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 01:03:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-27.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Evaluation of Treatment Thresholds for Helicoverpa zea (Lepidoptera: Noctuidae) in Non-Bt and Dual-Gene Bt Cotton: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 29-46, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE12-25.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 04:32:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE12-25.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>New York Honey Bees Evolved Resistance to Disease After Exposure to Varroa Mites: An international research team has some good news for the struggling honey bee and the millions of people who depend on them to pollinate crops and other plants. These valuable pollinators have faced widespread colony losses over the past decade, largely due to the spread of a predatory mite called the Varroa destructor. But the [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=4411&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2015/08/20/new-york-honey-bees-evolved-resistance-to-disease-after-exposure-to-varroa-mites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 09:10:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2015/08/20/new-york-honey-bees-evolved-resistance-to-disease-after-exposure-to-varroa-mites/</guid></item>
<item><title>Study Finds Very Few Wild Bee Species Pollinate Major Crops: A major international study finds that surprisingly few bee species are responsible for pollinating the world&#8217;s crops. The paper, published in Nature Communications, suggests that only two percent of wild bee species pollinate 80 percent of bee-pollinated crops worldwide. The study is one of the largest on bee pollination to date. While agricultural development and [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=4167&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2015/06/17/study-finds-very-few-wild-bee-species-pollinate-major-crops/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 05:22:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2015/06/17/study-finds-very-few-wild-bee-species-pollinate-major-crops/</guid></item>
<item><title>Species Richness and Seasonal Abundance of Billbugs, Sphenophorus spp., from South Carolina Golf Courses: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 20-28, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-31.00.20?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 22:45:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/1523-5475-31.00.20?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>The Development of an Enhanced Extension Agent Training to Create Butterfly Gardens in Louisiana: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 9-19, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-17.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:50:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-17.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Thermal Tolerance Characteristics of Two Honey Bee Races: Journal of Agricultural and Urban Entomology, <a href="http://www.bioone.org/toc/jaue/31/1">Volume 31, Issue 1</a>, Page 1-8, January 2015. <br /></title><link>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-05.1?af=R</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2015 02:23:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.bioone.org/doi/abs/10.3954/JAUE14-05.1?af=R</guid></item>
<item><title>Competition among Fungi and Bacteria in the Guts of Bees: A clearer picture is emerging of microorganisms that colonize the guts of some bee species, thanks to studies by a team of scientists with the USDA Agricultural Research Service (ARS) and the University of Texas-Austin (UTA). The effort, which examined competition among fungi and bacteria, could shed new light on how the microbes affect bee [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=1884&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2014/05/10/competition-among-fungi-and-bacteria-in-the-guts-of-bees/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 04:15:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2014/05/10/competition-among-fungi-and-bacteria-in-the-guts-of-bees/</guid></item>
<item><title>Adorable Bees That Live Inside Snail Shells - Wired: <table border="0" cellpadding="2" cellspacing="7" style="vertical-align: top;"><tr><td align="center" valign="top" width="80"><font style="font-size: 85%; font-family: arial,sans-serif;"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG8NlzX7LfJ4BFNgnEVTXRYmOP37g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;ei=LIc6V5CbEcTLwQGlnrYg&amp;url=http://www.wired.com/2014/04/adorable-bees-that-live-inside-snail-shells/"><img alt="" border="1" height="80" src="https://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcROSo43rq--E_wsN2rpnPq8Kd2hJQVORsd-lfHSvKiEoOHm-laAsHkhfb1Iq-iJmM5daOZO--Y" width="80" /><br /><font size="-2">Wired</font></a></font></td><td class="j" valign="top"><font style="font-size: 85%; font-family: arial,sans-serif;"><br /><div style="padding-top: 0.8em;"><img alt="" height="1" width="1" /></div><div class="lh"><a href="http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG8NlzX7LfJ4BFNgnEVTXRYmOP37g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;ei=LIc6V5CbEcTLwQGlnrYg&amp;url=http://www.wired.com/2014/04/adorable-bees-that-live-inside-snail-shells/"><b>Adorable <b>Bees</b> That Live Inside Snail Shells</b></a><br /><font size="-1"><b><font color="#6f6f6f">Wired</font></b></font><br /><font size="-1"><b>Osmia</b> bicolor is one of the first <b>bees</b> of spring, emerging as early as February in their native range of South England and Wales. As solitary <b>bees</b>, there are no queens and workers; females build their nests alone. Males emerge, mate, and then die.</font><br /><font class="p" size="-1"></font><br /><font class="p" size="-1"><a class="p" href="http://news.google.com/news/more?ncl=dHqT5HYjBMQxe9M&amp;authuser=0&amp;ned=us"><b></b></a></font></div></font></td></tr></table></title><link>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG8NlzX7LfJ4BFNgnEVTXRYmOP37g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;ei=LIc6V5CbEcTLwQGlnrYg&amp;url=http://www.wired.com/2014/04/adorable-bees-that-live-inside-snail-shells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 13:11:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://news.google.com/news/url?sa=t&amp;fd=R&amp;ct2=us&amp;usg=AFQjCNG8NlzX7LfJ4BFNgnEVTXRYmOP37g&amp;clid=c3a7d30bb8a4878e06b80cf16b898331&amp;ei=LIc6V5CbEcTLwQGlnrYg&amp;url=http://www.wired.com/2014/04/adorable-bees-that-live-inside-snail-shells/</guid></item>
<item><title>Australia Fits Thousands of Bees with Sensors to Monitor the Environment: Up to 5,000 sensors measuring 2.5mm x 2.5 mm are being fitted to the backs of bees in Hobart, Tasmania, before being released into the wild. It&#8217;s the first time such large numbers of insects have been used for environmental monitoring by using a technique known as &#8220;swarm sensing.&#8221; The research is being led by [&#8230;]<img alt="" border="0" height="1" src="https://pixel.wp.com/b.gif?host=entomologytoday.org&#038;blog=49318313&#038;post=1371&#038;subd=entomologytoday&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" /></title><link>https://entomologytoday.org/2014/01/15/australia-fits-thousands-of-bees-with-sensors-to-monitor-the-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 07:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://entomologytoday.org/2014/01/15/australia-fits-thousands-of-bees-with-sensors-to-monitor-the-environment/</guid></item>

</div>
<div id="footer">
<p id="aboutrawdog">Generated by
<a href="http://offog.org/code/rawdog.html">rawdog</a>
version 2.21
by <a href="mailto:ats@offog.org">Adam Sampson</a>.</p>
</div>
</body>
</html>
